<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-24T11:18:58+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The SUBSTATION</title><subtitle>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</subtitle><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><entry><title type="html">DIASPORA</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/diaspora/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DIASPORA" /><published>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/diaspora</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/diaspora/">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the concepts found in the first chapter of Australian author Greg Egan’s legendary science fiction masterpiece of the same name, DIASPORA presents a uniquely utopian reading of what life might be like if we surrender to the fact that software can be, and in fact is already, superhumanly organic. As we theorise and catastrophise about the perils of handing over control to an AI we often overlook the possibility that software could not only save our species but that it could also be a beautiful step in evolution towards an ethereal, non-body, consciousness. Using projection, illusions and lasers, a truly futuristic visual design houses an ensemble of extraordinary musicians who are charged with sonifying the complex and multi-layered build of a digital life-form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creative team is led by composer and audio-visual artist &lt;a href=&quot;https://robinfox.com.au/&quot;&gt;ROBIN FOX&lt;/a&gt; working in close collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chambermade.org&quot;&gt;CHAMBER MADE&lt;/a&gt; Artistic Director dramaturg and co-director TAMARA SAULWICK, co-composer and violinist  ERKKI VELTHEIM, video artist and system designer NICK ROUX, and musician / performers MADELEINE FLYNN (ondes musicales and Moog synth) and GEORGINA DARVIDIS (vocals and theremin), with lighting design by AMELIA LEVER-DAVIDSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;Melbourne International Arts Festival&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chambermade.org&quot;&gt;CHAMBER MADE&lt;/a&gt;. This project has been assisted by the Australian Government through the Australia Council.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/2019/info/packages-discounts/3plus-packages/&quot;&gt;Book three SUBSTATION x MIAF Events and save 15%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Inspired by the concepts found in the first chapter of Australian author Greg Egan’s legendary science fiction masterpiece of the same name, DIASPORA presents a uniquely utopian reading of what life might be like if we surrender to the fact that software can be, and in fact is already, superhumanly organic. As we theorise and catastrophise about the perils of handing over control to an AI we often overlook the possibility that software could not only save our species but that it could also be a beautiful step in evolution towards an ethereal, non-body, consciousness. Using projection, illusions and lasers, a truly futuristic visual design houses an ensemble of extraordinary musicians who are charged with sonifying the complex and multi-layered build of a digital life-form.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Diaspora.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">EVERYWHEN</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/everywhen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EVERYWHEN" /><published>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/everywhen</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/everywhen/">&lt;p&gt;EVERYWHEN creates a world of massed percussive objects in perpetual motion, exploring the transience of the physical and psychological structures we create as humans. 
A lone performer inhabits a teeming sonic environment, surrounded by a swarm of hovering objects that move in orbits of up to six meters. Utilizing a large-scale rotational truss structure, the work reveals the power of cyclic motion in sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gongs play themselves as they spin through the space, suspended chimes hum as they ricochet off each other, shells vibrate as they hover through the air and sheets of metal roar as they float in orbital trajectories. Concentric circles of stone and rubble accumulate beneath this shifting canopy of sound, evoking ritual geometries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dense, intricate and mesmerising. The audience is enveloped in a whirlpool of sound, augmented by an immersive rotational lighting system designed by Keith Tucker of Megafun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director, Composer, Performer – &lt;a href=&quot;http://matthiasschackarnott.com&quot;&gt;Matthias Schack-Arnott&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Robotics – Nick Roux, Lighting Designer - Keith Tucker &lt;br /&gt;
Sound Engineer – Tilman Robinson, Production Management - Megafun &lt;br /&gt;
Producer – Michaela Coventry - Sage Arts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;Melbourne International Arts Festival&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/2019/info/packages-discounts/3plus-packages/&quot;&gt;Book three SUBSTATION x MIAF Events and save 15%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">EVERYWHEN creates a world of massed percussive objects in perpetual motion, exploring the transience of the physical and psychological structures we create as humans. A lone performer inhabits a teeming sonic environment, surrounded by a swarm of hovering objects that move in orbits of up to six meters. Utilizing a large-scale rotational truss structure, the work reveals the power of cyclic motion in sound.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Everywhen.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">KUKANGENDAI (JPN)</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kukangendai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KUKANGENDAI (JPN)" /><published>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kukangendai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kukangendai/">&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;Melbourne International Arts Festival&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jpf.go.jp/e/index.html&quot;&gt;Japan Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;br /&gt; Japan’s avant-garde rock trio &lt;a href=&quot;http://kukangendai.com/&quot;&gt;KUKANGENDAI&lt;/a&gt; will perform an hour-long musical piece ORGAN as their debut in Australia. The band creates experimental music in live performances by dissecting and reconstructing rhythms and phrases. Their intense and captivating sound will thrill audiences throughout Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://http://kukangendai.com/&quot;&gt;KUKANGENDAI&lt;/a&gt; formed in 2006 with JUNYA NOGUCHI on guitar and vocals, KEISUKE KOYANO on bass guitar, and HIDEAKI YAMADA on drums. Their tracks are made through a process of editing, replicating, and deliberate error.  This creates a sense of distortion and places a burden on the performers, leading to their characteristically stoic and humorous live shows. In recent years, the band has attempted to construct and implement a form of live concert in which they go back and forth between playing multiple simultaneous songs in parallel, allowing the flow of time as a whole to manifest as a single unified rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;Melbourne International Arts Festival&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jpf.go.jp/e/index.html&quot;&gt;Japan Foundation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/2019/info/packages-discounts/3plus-packages/&quot;&gt;Book three SUBSTATION x MIAF Events and save 15%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">In collaboration with Melbourne International Arts Festival and the Japan Foundation, Japan’s avant-garde rock trio KUKANGENDAI will perform an hour-long musical piece ORGAN as their debut in Australia. The band creates experimental music in live performances by dissecting and reconstructing rhythms and phrases. Their intense and captivating sound will thrill audiences throughout Australia.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/KUKANGENDAI.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hi-Viz Practice Exchange</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/hi-viz-practice-exchange/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hi-Viz Practice Exchange" /><published>2019-07-04T11:02:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-04T11:02:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/hi-viz-practice-exchange</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/hi-viz-practice-exchange/">&lt;p&gt;Artists involved include &lt;strong&gt;Liza Lim, Cat Hope, Roslyn Oades, Madeleine Flynn, Carolyn Connors, Gian Slater, Kate Sulan&lt;/strong&gt; and more to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi-Viz&lt;/strong&gt; is for women and non-binary artists working across performance, sound and music. It is for everyone in this space, from emerging to established artists. &lt;strong&gt;Hi-Viz&lt;/strong&gt; is designed to bring performance-makers, directors, composers, and sound artists into conversation with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst there are many artists working in these crossover spaces, there are few opportunities outside of the framework of producing work, to gather and interrogate this area of practice. Each artform discipline brings with it quite distinct languages, skills, processes, conventions and expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi-Viz Practice Exchange&lt;/strong&gt; aims to begin conversations to unpack these differences in the hope of developing a richer understanding of the possibilities of cross-artform practice. Importantly, it is also a day for practitioners from the often quite discrete scenes of contemporary performance/theatre, sound art, and new/art music to meet one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day one is a day of presentations, practice interrogation, networking and art dates. Day two is a day of hands-on, interactive workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;www.chambermade.org&quot;&gt;Chamber Made.&lt;/a&gt; This event has been supported by the Helen Macpherson Smith Trust.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Artists involved include Liza Lim, Cat Hope, Roslyn Oades, Madeleine Flynn, Carolyn Connors, Gian Slater, Kate Sulan and more to come.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/HiVisHeroImage.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SUBTERRAIN/ UNDERSCORED</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/subterrain-slash-underscored/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SUBTERRAIN/
UNDERSCORED" /><published>2019-07-03T12:23:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-03T12:23:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/subterrain-slash-underscored</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/subterrain-slash-underscored/">&lt;p&gt;During the weekend of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openhousemelbourne.org/melbourne/the-weekend-july-2019/&quot;&gt;Open House Melbourne&lt;/a&gt;, The SUBSTATION presents SUBTERRAIN/UNDERSCORED, a free durational dance event created and choreographed by LINDA SASTRADIPRADJA and STUART SHUGG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performances of SUBTERRAIN are UNDERSCORED by dancing that has influenced the lineage of the performers: American Modern and Postmodern dance, traditional Javanese Court dance, and Wayang Kulit performances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together SUBTERRAIN/UNDERSCORED occupies The SUBSTATION’s many spaces, occurring at various times and locations within the building throughout the day. The audience is invited to experience SUBTERRAIN/UNDERSCORED through these ever-changing perspectives, to freely wander through and around the building as the dancing unfolds, shifting through and interacting with the cycles of natural daylight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through SUBTERRAIN/UNDERSCORED, SASTRADIPRADJA and  SHUGG will curate spaces within The SUBSTATION’s architecture to provoke a reconsideration of how, when and where it is possible to experience performed work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UNDERSCORED will be danced throughout the day with performances of SUBTERRAIN starting at 12pm and 3pm daily.
The SUBSTATION will be open for public access from 11am - 5pm daily.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">During the weekend of Open House Melbourne, The SUBSTATION presents SUBTERRAIN/UNDERSCORED, a free durational dance event created and choreographed by LINDA SASTRADIPRADJA and STUART SHUGG.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/subterrain-underscored.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Community bookings</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/community/community-bookings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Community bookings" /><published>2019-06-26T13:11:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-06-26T13:11:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/community/community-bookings</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/community/community-bookings/">&lt;p&gt;The SUBSTATION is dedicated to working with the local community through venue hire. The SUBSTATION has a number of hires each year allocated to community bookings that are booked via an application process. Community bookings provide opportunities for The SUBSTATION to engage in activities within their community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a local not for profit or community organisation please send through your event proposal including dates, number of guests and the reason for your event to Marisa Fiume on events@thesubstation.org.au&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">The SUBSTATION is dedicated to working with the local community through venue hire. The SUBSTATION has a number of hires each year allocated to community bookings that are booked via an application process. Community bookings provide opportunities for The SUBSTATION to engage in activities within their community.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/the-substation-community-bookings.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Loscil (CA), Rafael Anton Irisarri (USA), Joe Talia &amp;amp; Eiko Ishibashi (JPN) and Lost Few</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/loscil-rafael/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Loscil (CA), Rafael Anton Irisarri (USA), Joe Talia &amp; Eiko Ishibashi (JPN) and Lost Few" /><published>2019-06-21T12:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-06-21T12:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/loscil-rafael</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/loscil-rafael/">&lt;p&gt;The SUBSTATION and Room40 present a night of beautiful electronic exploration through an impressive cast of ambient masters – Loscil (CA), Rafael Anton Irisarri (USA), Joe Talia and Eiko Ishibashi (JPN) and Lost Few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loscil aka Scott Morgan from Vancouver derived his name from the “looping oscillator” function of Csound audio programming language. Yet since 2001 Loscil has been making more than just loops – bringing slow ambient textures exploring subjects like water and morning plain – leaving you wrapped in a sonic blanket of euphoria and aural bliss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining Loscil is one of New Yorks most celebrated ambient music makers, Rafael Anton Irisarri, a multi-instrumentalist, record producer, mastering engineer and curator. Irisarri’s music often has a mournful, elegiac quality, his compositions are deeply emotive and epic, like a symphony recording that’s been rescued from attic entombment after half a century. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tokyo-based electro-acoustic duo Eiko Ishibashi &amp;amp; Joe Talia, performing with flute, piano, analog tape, synthesizers and percussion. Together their work creates a dense harmonic sound world that exists somewhere between avant-garde improvisation and electronic exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining this spectacular line up is Lost Few, an audio-visual project by Melbourne-based experimental artist David Thomson. Lost Few will be debuting Between the Silence – a two person performance installation with visuals by Keith Deverell – showcasing ambient techno, disturbed electronics, processed instrumentation and sub-bass experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is general standing and relaxed seating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and Room40.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">The SUBSTATION and Room40 present a night of beautiful electronic exploration through an impressive cast of ambient masters – Loscil (CA), Rafael Anton Irisarri (USA), Joe Talia and Eiko Ishibashi (JPN) and Lost Few.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/loscil.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Young Researchers</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/community/young-researchers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Young Researchers" /><published>2019-06-18T16:13:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-06-18T16:13:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/community/young-researchers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/community/young-researchers/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Young Researchers&lt;/strong&gt; is a three day Visual Art program for students of Williamstown High school from Years 8, 9 and 10 to be held in August at The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The three days of art making will use a range of media particularly drawing, collage, painting and writing. Students will work with a practicing artist &lt;strong&gt;Hayley Millar-Baker&lt;/strong&gt; to create their own work and/or collaborative piece. This immersive program will assist students to extend their artistic skills and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Young Researchers is a three day Visual Art program for students of Williamstown High school from Years 8, 9 and 10 to be held in August at The SUBSTATION.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Young_Researchers.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Éliane Radigue</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/eliane-radigue/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Éliane Radigue" /><published>2019-06-18T15:11:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-06-18T15:11:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/eliane-radigue</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/eliane-radigue/">&lt;p&gt;French composer &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lovely.com/bios/radigue.html&quot;&gt;Éliane Radigue&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; holds a unique place in electronic music history. Her works, created for Arp 2500 synthesiser, are renowned for their hypnotic pulsing, reductive beauty and deep timbral palettes. Over the course of nearly five decades, &lt;strong&gt;Radigue&lt;/strong&gt; set a benchmark for minimalist electronic music and struck the tone for generations to come. More recently she has turned her ears to acoustic sources, working closely with a select group of musicians to create works that share the intense focus and beauty of her earlier pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate her work, &lt;strong&gt;Lionel Marchetti (FR), Cat Hope, Decibel,&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Lawrence English&lt;/strong&gt; come together to present an evening of electronic music diffusions and delicate acoustics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and Room40.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">French composer Éliane Radigue holds a unique place in electronic music history. Her works, created for Arp 2500 synthesiser, are renowned for their hypnotic pulsing, reductive beauty and deep timbral palettes. Over the course of nearly five decades, Radigue set a benchmark for minimalist electronic music and struck the tone for generations to come. More recently she has turned her ears to acoustic sources, working closely with a select group of musicians to create works that share the intense focus and beauty of her earlier pieces.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Eliane-Radigue.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ONO PRESENTS</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/ono2019/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ONO PRESENTS" /><published>2019-06-18T12:36:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-06-18T12:36:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/ono2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/ono2019/">&lt;p&gt;Continuing the journey towards a collective understanding of rhythm and sound, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.o-n-o.com.au/&quot;&gt;ONO&lt;/a&gt; returns for their third instalment at The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pack a cushion, or grab one provided and snuggle down for a night of high fidelity storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part performance, part installation, ONO creates a platform for music most often reserved for private enjoyment. Ambient and experimental sounds flow freely via communal conditions of warmth, comfort and intimacy between listener and performer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often intense but always rewarding, room, artist and audience all form part of the instrument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/grandriver-de&quot;&gt;GRAND RIVER&lt;/a&gt; live, Spazio Disponibile/One Instrument (ITA/NL)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.residentadvisor.net/dj/chrismnmlssgs/biography&quot;&gt;CHRIS SSG&lt;/a&gt; MNML SSGS (JPN)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bodypromise.bandcamp.com/track/fia-fiell-ladder&quot;&gt;FÍA FIELL&lt;/a&gt; Nice Music/Body Promise 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sleep-d.bandcamp.com/&quot;&gt;SOFT HIGH&lt;/a&gt; aka. Sleep D (Butter Sessions)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Continuing the journey towards a collective understanding of rhythm and sound, ONO returns for their third instalment at The SUBSTATION.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Ono2019.jpg" /></entry></feed>