<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-05T17:51:21+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/</id><title type="html">The SUBSTATION</title><subtitle>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</subtitle><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><entry><title type="html">BIN DIXON-WARD</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bin-dixon-ward/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BIN DIXON-WARD" /><published>2018-06-12T14:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-06-12T14:40:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bin-dixon-ward</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bin-dixon-ward/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;bin.dixon-ward.com&quot;&gt;BIN DIXON-WARD&lt;/a&gt;’s work uses 3D printing to explore the links between the geometry of urban and industrial infrastructure across the West through contemporary jewellery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Melbourne’s sparkling CBD towers in the rearview mirror, the West Gate freeway is an artery through rapidly changing industrial and suburban landscapes. ‘This is what’s left of the West Gate’ examines the region by drawing upon satellite images to reveal a not just a landscape featuring the massive infrastructure of industrial and manufacturing industries but coastal wetlands, housing, parklands and sports fields, shipping and cleared ‘ghost sites’, evidence of past industrial histories, all laid out along a lacelike network of creeks, roads and railways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BIN DIXON-WARD’s jewellery reflects the impact of the changing role of the western suburbs using technologies of the ‘next industrial age’. Using the same tools that are used to design cities, and buildings to design jewellery but on a micro scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and The &lt;a href=&quot;artandindustryfestival.com.au&quot;&gt;ART &amp;amp; INDUSTRY FESTIVAL.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">BIN DIXON-WARD’s work uses 3D printing to explore the links between the geometry of urban and industrial infrastructure across the West through contemporary jewellery.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Bin-Dixon-Ward.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Newport Archives</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Newport Archives" /><published>2018-05-12T12:56:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T12:56:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/">&lt;p&gt;NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport.  Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newport Archives is available by appointment. Email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@thesubstation.org.au&quot;&gt;info@thesubstation.org.au&lt;/a&gt; to book. Each session runs for 40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio Design by JOE TALIA.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commissioned by The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport. Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/newport-archives-2017.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NEWER VOLCANICS</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newer-volcanics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NEWER VOLCANICS" /><published>2018-05-10T14:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-10T14:40:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newer-volcanics</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newer-volcanics/">&lt;p&gt;Musicians MARITA DYSON and STUART FLANAGAN, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theorbweavers.com/&quot;&gt;The ORBWEAVERS&lt;/a&gt;, present the culmination of their research into the changes that occurred to the waterways of Melbourne’s West in the late 19th and 20th centuries. NEWER VOLCANICS explores the industrial history and environmental change and the lives of people who lived and worked the waterways of Melbourne’s West through a concert of music, poetry and drawings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION in association with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mistletone.net/&quot;&gt;MISTLETONE RECORDS&lt;/a&gt;. Supported by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slv.vic.gov.au/&quot;&gt;State Library of Victoria&lt;/a&gt; and Creative Victoria.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Musicians MARITA DYSON and STUART FLANAGAN, The ORBWEAVERS, present the culmination of their research into the changes that occurred to the waterways of Melbourne’s West in the late 19th and 20th centuries. NEWER VOLCANICS explores the industrial history and environmental change and the lives of people who lived and worked the waterways of Melbourne’s West through a concert of music, poetry and drawings.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Orbweavers.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Bridge</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-bridge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Bridge" /><published>2018-05-09T15:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-09T15:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-bridge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-bridge/">&lt;p&gt;A highly regarded verbatim play by the late VICKI REYNOLDS, THE BRIDGE will be presented within a multi-media installation featuring video projection and design by BINDI COLE CHOCKA and music by JAMES HENRY. Directed by DONNA JACKSON and performed by an ensemble cast of actors and community members, THE BRIDGE revisits the collapse of a giant span of Melbourne’s Westgate Bridge in 1970 that claimed the lives of thirty-five workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This powerful installation and theatrical collaboration consider the historical impact and current ramifications of this event through the lens of past and present politics. The West Gate Bridge is more than a physical bridge; it is a link to the past, family and friends, between different cultures and into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and The ART &amp;amp; INDUSTRY FESTIVAL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supported by Hobsons Bay City Council, Hubcap Productions and the Australian Government through the Australia Council, its arts funding advisory body.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">A highly regarded verbatim play by the late VICKI REYNOLDS, THE BRIDGE will be presented within a multi-media installation featuring video projection and design by BINDI COLE CHOCKA and music by JAMES HENRY. Directed by DONNA JACKSON and performed by an ensemble cast of actors and community members, THE BRIDGE revisits the collapse of a giant span of Melbourne’s Westgate Bridge in 1970 that claimed the lives of thirty-five workers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/The-Bridge.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Defunctionalised Autonomous Objects</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/steven-rhall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Defunctionalised Autonomous Objects" /><published>2018-05-08T15:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-08T15:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/steven-rhall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/steven-rhall/">&lt;p&gt;Art is just a frame of mind. &lt;a href=&quot;http://stevenrhall.com/&quot;&gt;STEVEN RHALL&lt;/a&gt; takes the frame out of the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first art museums were spaces of conquest when they weren’t showcasing items pillaged from Non European cultures, it was the very bodies of those people put on display. Taungurung visual artist STEVEN RHALL dismantles the gallery as imperial machine, calling into question the very idea of Aboriginal Art as a classification in a series of installations which interrogate various contexts surrounding First Nation art practice and, it’s presentation for a public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Located at the flashpoints of the European art canon and First Nations art practice, RHALL’s work roams across forms – performance, video, text and photography – and in recent years his playful and thought-provoking creations have been seen in the National Gallery of Victoria, ACCA and the Centre for Contemporary Photography. DEFUNCTIONALISED AUTONOMOUS OBJECTS is RHALL’s first major solo exhibition and confirms his place at the leading edge of a new generation of Australian artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;. 
Defunctionalised Autonomous Objects is supported by the Victorian Government through Creative Victoria, Australia Council for the Arts and Creative Partnerships Australia through their Plus 1 program.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Art is just a frame of mind. STEVEN RHALL takes the frame out of the picture.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/steven.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">100 KEYBOARDS</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/100-keyboards/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100 KEYBOARDS" /><published>2018-05-07T14:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-07T14:40:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/100-keyboards</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/100-keyboards/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Asuna’s live performances are an experience; textured soundscapes that blur the lines between art and music.”
– Tokyo Art Beat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music of multi-instrumental sound artist &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/aaaaasunaaaaa/&quot;&gt;ASUNA&lt;/a&gt; has reshaped multiple facets of the experimental music scene of Japan, from ambient and drone to improvisation. His landmark work 100 Keyboards is a site-specific listening experience in which one hundred cheap plastic keyboards play the same key, generating an undulating sonic harmony both mesmerising and mysterious. The crowd of sounds comes to take on its own kind of mass, while subtle acoustic variations emerge, hover and retreat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the late 90s ASUNA has created experimental sound works that vault genre divides, crossing from hip hop to hardcore punk to freak folk noise and low-fi pop. His performances might feature sound sources as diverse as popping candy, wind-up toys and kazoos, but the playfulness of his compositions belie the profound sensibilities of a true avant-garde artist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and MELBOURNE FESTIVAL. 100 Keyboards is supported by &lt;a href=&quot;https://asialink.unimelb.edu.au/home&quot;&gt;Asialink&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">“Asuna’s live performances are an experience; textured soundscapes that blur the lines between art and music.” – Tokyo Art Beat</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/ASUNA.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">PLAYING UP</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/playing-up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PLAYING UP" /><published>2018-05-06T14:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-06T14:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/playing-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/playing-up/">&lt;p&gt;Make clothes out of food, remote control your parents, invent your own form of sports, search for miracles, deconstruct electrical devices, build what-happens-next-machines!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PLAYING UP is an artwork by Sibylle Peters of Theatre of Research, exploring the potential of Live Art to bridge generations and suggest different ways of looking at the world. Drawing on key Live Art themes and seminal works, PLAYING UP takes the form of a game played by adults and kids together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Children, grown-ups, families and friends are all welcome. Pick a card, follow the instructions, create your own piece of Live Art, and perform it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and MELBOURNE FRINGE. Published and produced by the LIVE ART DEVELOPMENT AGENCY (UK), THEATRE OF RESEARCH (Germany), and TATE EARLY YEARS AND FAMILY PROGRAMME (UK).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Make clothes out of food, remote control your parents, invent your own form of sports, search for miracles, deconstruct electrical devices, build what-happens-next-machines!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/PLAYING-UP.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">CONCRETE IMPERMANENCE</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/concrete-impermanence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CONCRETE IMPERMANENCE" /><published>2018-05-05T15:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-05T15:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/concrete-impermanence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/concrete-impermanence/">&lt;p&gt;Adelaide based choreographer and artist, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alisoncurrie.com/&quot;&gt;ALISON CURRIE&lt;/a&gt; presents her new work CONCRETE IMPERMANENCE, tackling global and personal instability, environmental disaster and personal trauma through the connection of sculptural objects and people on stage. Through these relationships and environments, she reveals the fragility of human existence; in its tragedy, its poetic beauty and in the inevitable reality of a fragile existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and ALISON CURRIE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supported by &lt;a href=&quot;http://insitearts.com.au/&quot;&gt;Insite Arts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://arts.sa.gov.au/&quot;&gt;Arts SA&lt;/a&gt;, Australia Council for the Arts, &lt;a href=&quot;http://restlessdance.org/&quot;&gt;Restless Dance Theatre&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lwd.com.au/&quot;&gt;LWDance Hub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://access2arts.org.au/&quot;&gt;Access2Arts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adelaidefestivalcentre.com.au/&quot;&gt;Adelaide Festival Centre.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Adelaide based choreographer and artist, ALISON CURRIE presents her new work CONCRETE IMPERMANENCE, tackling global and personal instability, environmental disaster and personal trauma through the connection of sculptural objects and people on stage. Through these relationships and environments, she reveals the fragility of human existence; in its tragedy, its poetic beauty and in the inevitable reality of a fragile existence.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Concrete.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">NONCOMPETE</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/noncompete/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NONCOMPETE" /><published>2018-05-04T15:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-04T15:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/noncompete</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/noncompete/">&lt;p&gt;NONCOMPETE is a post-human music, sculpture and installation featuring new electro-mechanical robotic instruments with hundreds of moving parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALISDAIR MACINDOE’s work is a musical reflection on the idea that digital technology is a new life that we are currently gestating and though it is made by us and reflects our development, the point where technology has agency and its own agenda is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">NONCOMPETE is a post-human music, sculpture and installation featuring new electro-mechanical robotic instruments with hundreds of moving parts.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Alisdair-M.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Design Plot</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-design-plot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Design Plot" /><published>2018-05-03T15:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-03T15:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-design-plot</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-design-plot/">&lt;p&gt;THE DESIGN PLOT is an ongoing performance project by &lt;a href=&quot;http://shelleylasica.com/&quot;&gt;SHELLEY LASICA&lt;/a&gt; including collaborations with six dancers and a cinematographer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THE DESIGN PLOT uses the structure of dancing, with the discipline of scenography as a source for its design and development. Responding to the context, this utterance of the project will take over The SUBSTATION, unfolding through a methodology that includes open research sessions, public talks, installation and the development of performance mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this suite, and for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openhousemelbourne.org/&quot;&gt;Open House Melbourne.&lt;/a&gt;, GREATER UNION is a new duet work for Lasica and Timothy Harvey with whom she has worked with over fifteen years. The duet considers the unstable specificity of particular project and the notion of the archive, or the organism of ‘the body work’. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shelley Lasica will also be in conversation with an independent writer, curator, and a part-time academic in the School of Architecture and Design at RMIT Phip Murray, discussing her own choreographic history in relation to collaboration and documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dancers: ELLEN DAVIES, TIMOTHY HARVEY, LOUELLA MAY HOGAN, DANIEL NEWELL, LILIAN STEINER AND JO WHITE &lt;br /&gt;
Cinematographer: JAMES WRIGHT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project has previously been presented at RMIT Design Hub, MPavilion, Gertrude Glasshouse, Minanoie, the Royal Melbourne Tennis Club and Sutton Projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openhousemelbourne.org/&quot;&gt;Open House Melbourne.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">THE DESIGN PLOT is an ongoing performance project by SHELLEY LASICA including collaborations with six dancers and a cinematographer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/The-Design.jpg" /></entry></feed>