<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-08-01T11:45:12+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The SUBSTATION</title><subtitle>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</subtitle><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><entry><title type="html">Act To Prevent Men’s Violence Against Women</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/community/act-to-prevent-mens-violence-against-women/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Act To Prevent Men’s Violence Against Women" /><published>2019-07-31T15:49:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T15:49:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/community/act-to-prevent-mens-violence-against-women</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/community/act-to-prevent-mens-violence-against-women/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women’s Health West&lt;/strong&gt; launched a resource about the prevention of violence against women at The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Act To Prevent Men’s Violence Against Women: a Guide for Community Action&lt;/strong&gt; aims to support community groups in Melbourne’s west to take action to prevent men’s violence against women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers include Tarang Chawla, Nelly Thomas, Working Together with Men, Women Making it Happen, Janet Galpin of Boon Wurrung Foundation, and Susan Timmins and Shelley Tait of Women’s Health West.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Supported by HealthWest, Hobsons Bay City Council, Moonee Valley City Council, cohealth, Western Bulldogs, City of Melbourne, Inner North West PCP, Djerriwarrh Health Services (Health Hospital Community), City of Melton, Victoria University, Melbourne Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lj-OqfNxp2s&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video by Teagan Glenane.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Women’s Health West launched a resource about the prevention of violence against women at The SUBSTATION.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/womenshealthforum.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Warchild Benefit Concert</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/community/war-child/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Warchild Benefit Concert" /><published>2019-07-31T13:14:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T13:14:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/community/war-child</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/community/war-child/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warchild Benefit Concert&lt;/strong&gt; will showcase bands from all year levels at &lt;strong&gt;Williamstown High&lt;/strong&gt; for a full evening of music. All proceeds will go towards the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.warchild.org/&quot;&gt;War Child&lt;/a&gt; charity supporting families affected by war. War Child empowers families to claim their rights, develop to their full potential and contribute to a peaceful future for themselves and their communities.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Warchild Benefit Concert will showcase bands from all year levels at Williamstown High for a full evening of music. All proceeds will go towards the War Child charity supporting families affected by war. War Child empowers families to claim their rights, develop to their full potential and contribute to a peaceful future for themselves and their communities.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/warchild.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Untimely Geographies</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/untimely-geographies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Untimely Geographies" /><published>2019-07-30T13:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-30T13:30:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/untimely-geographies</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/untimely-geographies/">&lt;p&gt;UNTIMELY GEOGRAPHIES, curated by Artistic Director KELLI ALRED, investigates relationships between individuals, communities and power structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featuring multi-channel video works by London-Istanbul based duo NOOR AFSHAN MIRZA and BRAD BUTLER,  Australian artist REKO RENNIE and Kazakhstani artist ALMAGUL MENLIBAYEYA, the exhibition examines critical moments of social transformation across different eras, cultures and geographies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition sheds light on postcolonial narratives by juxtaposing the work of artists from Australia and central Asia. It brings a personal story – which references a matriarchal Indigenous culture from northern NSW – into dialogue with contemporary feminist perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paying homage to cinematic genres such as the road movie and film noir, the artists draw on cosmology, crash theory, symbolism and myth to address questions about cultural identity, inequality and agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilising verbal and non-verbal language systems, the participating artists blend fantasy with fact to inspire fresh perspectives on historical events and their intergenerational implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.channelsfestival.net.au&quot;&gt;Channels Festival&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;International artists Almagul Menlibayeva (Kazakhstan/Germany) and Noor Afshan Mirza (Turkey/United Kingdom) are undertaking four-week residencies in Melbourne with support from Channels Festival and RMIT University School of Art through SITUATE.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">UNTIMELY GEOGRAPHIES, curated by Artistic Director KELLI ALRED, investigates relationships between individuals, communities and power structures.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/RekoRennie.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SIGNIFICANT ENCOUNTERS</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/tim-darbyshire/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SIGNIFICANT ENCOUNTERS" /><published>2019-07-24T12:16:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-24T12:16:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/tim-darbyshire</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/tim-darbyshire/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;www.timdarbyshirestudio.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tim Darbyshire&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; creates nuanced, dynamic and expansive choreography and performance – 
Drawing from visual, aural, spatial and tactile fields, whilst maintaining the body as a fulcrum. His work circulates around experimental practices, semiotics, architecture, site, body and object specificity. His projects wrestle between deconstructive and subliminal tensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He studied Dance at Queensland University of Technology (2003), attended DanceWEB scholarship program (2006 and 2009), completed Formation d’artiste Chorégraphique at Centre National de Danse Contemporaine (France 2006-2007) and obtained a Masters in Performing Arts from Iceland University of the Arts (2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He has presented his work Buckets and Other Things, More or Less Concrete, Stampede the Stampede, Tainted Title and Significant Encounters in a range of contexts including Dance Massive (AU), Keir Choreographic Awards (AU), Campbelltown Arts Centre (AU), Théâtre de la Cité internationale (FR), Dansenhus (NO), Teatro São João (PT), Noorderzon Festival (NL), Zodiak Centre for New Dance (FI), Tanzhaus Zürich (CH) and Reykjavik Dance Festival/Everybody’s Spectacular (IS).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Tim Darbyshire creates nuanced, dynamic and expansive choreography and performance – Drawing from visual, aural, spatial and tactile fields, whilst maintaining the body as a fulcrum. His work circulates around experimental practices, semiotics, architecture, site, body and object specificity. His projects wrestle between deconstructive and subliminal tensions.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Relational.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">DIASPORA</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/diaspora/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DIASPORA" /><published>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/diaspora</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/diaspora/">&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the concepts found in the first chapter of Australian author Greg Egan’s legendary science fiction masterpiece of the same name, DIASPORA presents a uniquely utopian reading of what life might be like if we surrender to the fact that software can be, and in fact is already, superhumanly organic. As we theorise and catastrophise about the perils of handing over control to an AI we often overlook the possibility that software could not only save our species but that it could also be a beautiful step in evolution towards an ethereal, non-body, consciousness. Using projection, illusions and lasers, a truly futuristic visual design houses an ensemble of extraordinary musicians who are charged with sonifying the complex and multi-layered build of a digital life-form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The creative team is led by composer and audio-visual artist &lt;a href=&quot;https://robinfox.com.au/&quot;&gt;ROBIN FOX&lt;/a&gt; working in close collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chambermade.org&quot;&gt;CHAMBER MADE&lt;/a&gt; Artistic Director dramaturg and co-director TAMARA SAULWICK, co-composer and violinist  ERKKI VELTHEIM, video artist and system designer NICK ROUX, and musician / performers MADELEINE FLYNN (ondes musicales and Moog synth) and GEORGINA DARVIDIS (vocals and theremin), with lighting design by AMELIA LEVER-DAVIDSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;Melbourne International Arts Festival&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chambermade.org&quot;&gt;CHAMBER MADE&lt;/a&gt;. This project has been assisted by the Australian Government through the Australia Council.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/2019/info/packages-discounts/3plus-packages/&quot;&gt;Book three SUBSTATION x MIAF Events and save 15%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Inspired by the concepts found in the first chapter of Australian author Greg Egan’s legendary science fiction masterpiece of the same name, DIASPORA presents a uniquely utopian reading of what life might be like if we surrender to the fact that software can be, and in fact is already, superhumanly organic. As we theorise and catastrophise about the perils of handing over control to an AI we often overlook the possibility that software could not only save our species but that it could also be a beautiful step in evolution towards an ethereal, non-body, consciousness. Using projection, illusions and lasers, a truly futuristic visual design houses an ensemble of extraordinary musicians who are charged with sonifying the complex and multi-layered build of a digital life-form.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Diaspora.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">EVERYWHEN</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/everywhen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EVERYWHEN" /><published>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/everywhen</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/everywhen/">&lt;p&gt;EVERYWHEN creates a world of massed percussive objects in perpetual motion, exploring the transience of the physical and psychological structures we create as humans. 
A lone performer inhabits a teeming sonic environment, surrounded by a swarm of hovering objects that move in orbits of up to six meters. Utilizing a large-scale rotational truss structure, the work reveals the power of cyclic motion in sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gongs play themselves as they spin through the space, suspended chimes hum as they ricochet off each other, shells vibrate as they hover through the air and sheets of metal roar as they float in orbital trajectories. Concentric circles of stone and rubble accumulate beneath this shifting canopy of sound, evoking ritual geometries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dense, intricate and mesmerising. The audience is enveloped in a whirlpool of sound, augmented by an immersive rotational lighting system designed by Keith Tucker of Megafun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Director, Composer, Performer – &lt;a href=&quot;http://matthiasschackarnott.com&quot;&gt;Matthias Schack-Arnott&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Robotics – Nick Roux &lt;br /&gt;
Lighting Designer - Keith Tucker &lt;br /&gt;
Sound Engineer – Tilman Robinson &lt;br /&gt;
Production Management - Megafun &lt;br /&gt;
Producer – Michaela Coventry / Sage Arts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;Melbourne International Arts Festival&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/2019/info/packages-discounts/3plus-packages/&quot;&gt;Book three SUBSTATION x MIAF Events and save 15%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">EVERYWHEN creates a world of massed percussive objects in perpetual motion, exploring the transience of the physical and psychological structures we create as humans. A lone performer inhabits a teeming sonic environment, surrounded by a swarm of hovering objects that move in orbits of up to six meters. Utilizing a large-scale rotational truss structure, the work reveals the power of cyclic motion in sound.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Everywhen.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">KUKANGENDAI (JPN)</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kukangendai/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KUKANGENDAI (JPN)" /><published>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-16T14:30:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kukangendai</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kukangendai/">&lt;p&gt;In collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;Melbourne International Arts Festival&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jpf.go.jp/e/index.html&quot;&gt;Japan Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;br /&gt; Japan’s avant-garde rock trio &lt;a href=&quot;http://kukangendai.com/&quot;&gt;KUKANGENDAI&lt;/a&gt; will perform an hour-long musical piece ORGAN as their debut in Australia. The band creates experimental music in live performances by dissecting and reconstructing rhythms and phrases. Their intense and captivating sound will thrill audiences throughout Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://http://kukangendai.com/&quot;&gt;KUKANGENDAI&lt;/a&gt; formed in 2006 with JUNYA NOGUCHI on guitar and vocals, KEISUKE KOYANO on bass guitar, and HIDEAKI YAMADA on drums. Their tracks are made through a process of editing, replicating, and deliberate error.  This creates a sense of distortion and places a burden on the performers, leading to their characteristically stoic and humorous live shows. In recent years, the band has attempted to construct and implement a form of live concert in which they go back and forth between playing multiple simultaneous songs in parallel, allowing the flow of time as a whole to manifest as a single unified rhythm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;Melbourne International Arts Festival&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jpf.go.jp/e/index.html&quot;&gt;Japan Foundation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/2019/info/packages-discounts/3plus-packages/&quot;&gt;Book three SUBSTATION x MIAF Events and save 15%&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">In collaboration with Melbourne International Arts Festival and the Japan Foundation, Japan’s avant-garde rock trio KUKANGENDAI will perform an hour-long musical piece ORGAN as their debut in Australia. The band creates experimental music in live performances by dissecting and reconstructing rhythms and phrases. Their intense and captivating sound will thrill audiences throughout Australia.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/KUKANGENDAI.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hi-Viz Practice Exchange</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/hi-viz-practice-exchange/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hi-Viz Practice Exchange" /><published>2019-07-04T11:02:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-04T11:02:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/hi-viz-practice-exchange</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/hi-viz-practice-exchange/">&lt;p&gt;Artists involved include &lt;strong&gt;Liza Lim, Cat Hope, Roslyn Oades, Madeleine Flynn, Carolyn Connors, Gian Slater, Kate Sulan&lt;/strong&gt; and more to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi-Viz&lt;/strong&gt; is for women and non-binary artists working across performance, sound and music. It is for everyone in this space, from emerging to established artists. &lt;strong&gt;Hi-Viz&lt;/strong&gt; is designed to bring performance-makers, directors, composers, and sound artists into conversation with one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst there are many artists working in these crossover spaces, there are few opportunities outside of the framework of producing work, to gather and interrogate this area of practice. Each artform discipline brings with it quite distinct languages, skills, processes, conventions and expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hi-Viz Practice Exchange&lt;/strong&gt; aims to begin conversations to unpack these differences in the hope of developing a richer understanding of the possibilities of cross-artform practice. Importantly, it is also a day for practitioners from the often quite discrete scenes of contemporary performance/theatre, sound art, and new/art music to meet one another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day one is a day of presentations, practice interrogation, networking and art dates. Day two is a day of hands-on, interactive workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;www.chambermade.org&quot;&gt;Chamber Made.&lt;/a&gt; This event has been supported by the Helen Macpherson Smith Trust.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Artists involved include Liza Lim, Cat Hope, Roslyn Oades, Madeleine Flynn, Carolyn Connors, Gian Slater, Kate Sulan and more to come.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/HiVisHeroImage.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SUBTERRAIN/ UNDERSCORED</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/subterrain-slash-underscored/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SUBTERRAIN/
UNDERSCORED" /><published>2019-07-03T12:23:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-07-03T12:23:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/subterrain-slash-underscored</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/subterrain-slash-underscored/">&lt;p&gt;During the weekend of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openhousemelbourne.org/melbourne/the-weekend-july-2019/&quot;&gt;Open House Melbourne&lt;/a&gt;, The SUBSTATION presents SUBTERRAIN/UNDERSCORED, a free durational dance event created and choreographed by LINDA SASTRADIPRADJA and STUART SHUGG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performances of SUBTERRAIN are UNDERSCORED by dancing that has influenced the lineage of the performers: American Modern and Postmodern dance, traditional Javanese Court dance, and Wayang Kulit performances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together SUBTERRAIN/UNDERSCORED occupies The SUBSTATION’s many spaces, occurring at various times and locations within the building throughout the day. The audience is invited to experience SUBTERRAIN/UNDERSCORED through these ever-changing perspectives, to freely wander through and around the building as the dancing unfolds, shifting through and interacting with the cycles of natural daylight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through SUBTERRAIN/UNDERSCORED, SASTRADIPRADJA and  SHUGG will curate spaces within The SUBSTATION’s architecture to provoke a reconsideration of how, when and where it is possible to experience performed work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UNDERSCORED will be danced throughout the day with performances of SUBTERRAIN starting at 12pm and 3pm daily.
The SUBSTATION will be open for public access from 11am - 5pm daily.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">During the weekend of Open House Melbourne, The SUBSTATION presents SUBTERRAIN/UNDERSCORED, a free durational dance event created and choreographed by LINDA SASTRADIPRADJA and STUART SHUGG.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/subterrain-underscored.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Community bookings</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/community/community-bookings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Community bookings" /><published>2019-06-26T13:11:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-06-26T13:11:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/community/community-bookings</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/community/community-bookings/">&lt;p&gt;The SUBSTATION is dedicated to working with the local community through venue hire. The SUBSTATION has a number of hires each year allocated to community bookings that are booked via an application process. Community bookings provide opportunities for The SUBSTATION to engage in activities within their community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a local not for profit or community organisation please send through your event proposal including dates, number of guests and the reason for your event to Marisa Fiume on events@thesubstation.org.au&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">The SUBSTATION is dedicated to working with the local community through venue hire. The SUBSTATION has a number of hires each year allocated to community bookings that are booked via an application process. Community bookings provide opportunities for The SUBSTATION to engage in activities within their community.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/the-substation-community-bookings.jpg" /></entry></feed>