<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The SUBSTATION</title>
    <description>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</description>
    <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 11:31:10 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 11:31:10 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Tribe</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;live-from-a-backyard-in-newport&quot;&gt;LIVE FROM A BACKYARD IN NEWPORT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After sell-out seasons at Sydney Festival and Belvoir St Theatre, &lt;a href=&quot;http://urbantheatre.com.au&quot;&gt;URBAN THEATRE PROJECTS&lt;/a&gt;’ THE TRIBE comes to The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performed by HAZEM SHAMMAS, THE TRIBE is a story of belonging and family, told by the small boy, Bani. At the heart of THE TRIBE is Bani’s love for his Tayta, his grandmother and core presence in his life, who carries all the truths of ‘The Tribe’ – a small Muslim sect who fled to Australia from Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking place in a Newport backyard, performed alongside cellist and composer OOHAGH SHERRARD, SHAMMAS’s Bani is like a visionary child channeling a Bedouin storyteller. Based on MICHAEL MOHAMMED AHMAD’s award-winning novel, &lt;a href=&quot;http://giramondopublishing.com/product/the-tribe&quot;&gt;THE TRIBE&lt;/a&gt; is an open invitation to listen to an Arab-Australian story from our backyard, in our backyards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adapted by Michael Mohammed Ahmad and Janice Muller&lt;br /&gt;
Based on the novel by Michael Mohammed Ahmad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: Janice Muller&lt;br /&gt;
Performer: Hazem Shammas
Composer and Performer: Oonagh Sherrard
Production Manager: Frank Mainoo
Producer: Urban Theatre Projects&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 10:54:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-tribe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-tribe/</guid>
        
        
        <category>whats-on</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>C A V E S  Off-site</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;CURATED BY &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stormgold.net&quot;&gt;STORM GOLD&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://kezhughes.tumblr.com&quot;&gt;KEZ HUGHES&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cavesgallery.com&quot;&gt;CAVES&lt;/a&gt; is a curated, not-for-profit art space in Melbourne, Australia. Established in 2014 by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stormgold.net&quot;&gt;STORM GOLD&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://kezhughes.tumblr.com&quot;&gt;KEZ HUGHES&lt;/a&gt;, the gallery began operation in February 2015 in the Nicholas Building in Melbourne CBD. The gallery aims to engage with and exhibit Australian and international artists as a means to connect with diverse modes of artistic practice. C A V E S  OFF-SITE expands GOLD and HUGHES’ interest to curate and exhibit in spaces beyond the CAVES gallery walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhibiting artists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Olga Bennett, Lily Benson (USA), Fernando do Campo (USA/AUS), William Daniels (UK), Naomi Eller, 
Andrea Jewel, Annika Koops, Alex Pittendrigh, Daniel Sinsel (UK), Ross Taylor (UK), Michelle Ussher (UK/AUS), Anna Varendorff, Rudi Williams, 
Zilverster (Sharon Goodwin &amp;amp; Irene Hanenbergh)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 10:35:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/c-a-v-e-s-off-site/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/c-a-v-e-s-off-site/</guid>
        
        
        <category>whats-on</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ONO</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Part music performance, part installation, ONO is a place to gather, listen and share. Drawing on traditions of oral storytelling, four musical offerings will each spin a yarn of ambient and abstract sounds in the belly of The SUBSTATION. ONO seeks to break down the usual back and forth between artist and listener, to create an inclusive and reverberating space of exchange. Bring your imagination on an excursion into outer sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featuring &lt;a href=&quot;http://soundcloud.com/analogueattic&quot;&gt;ALBRECHT LA’BROOY&lt;/a&gt; (Analogue Attic), &lt;a href=&quot;http://burntfriedman.com&quot;&gt;BURNT FRIEDMAN&lt;/a&gt; (Nonplace/GER), &lt;a href=&quot;http://soundcloud.com/nuel&quot;&gt;NUEL&lt;/a&gt; (Aquaplano/ITA) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://soundcloud.com/sleepd&quot;&gt;SLEEP D&lt;/a&gt; (Butter Sessions)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 18:21:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/ono/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/ono/</guid>
        
        
        <category>whats-on</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pose Like This</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent VCA graduates, &lt;a href=&quot;http://cargocollective.com/emmacollard/&quot;&gt;EMMA COLLARD&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://rafaellamcdonald.com.au&quot;&gt;RAFAELLA MCDONALD&lt;/a&gt;, collaborate in their first major exhibition together, POSE LIKE THIS. Developing the work in The SUBSTATION’s galleries, a series of sets for performances spill throughout the space. Utilising materials such as brightly-coloured paint, wood, plastic, mirrors, fabric and found objects, the duo create a range of overlapping environments, intermingled with pre-recorded videos, live recordings, performances and bodily improvisations. Reflecting on various representations of the body, self and the frame, the large network of images and actions examine if a single moment can be flattened or if it must keep circulating through chaos to function.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 15:21:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/pose-like-this/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/pose-like-this/</guid>
        
        
        <category>whats-on</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>THE LONG STRING INSTRUMENT</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ellenfullman.com/]&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ELLEN FULLMAN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the creator of the LONG STRING INSTRUMENT, in which rosin-coated fingers brush across dozens of highly tensioned metallic strings, spanning up to thirty metres in length. When played, this stunning and unique instrument produces a chorus of minimal, organ-like overtones. The experience for an audience has been described akin to standing inside an enormous grand piano.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Melbourne, FULLMAN will collaborate with acclaimed composer and cellist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theresawong.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THERESA WONG&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Together they layer the harmonic possibilities of the cello with the undulating overtones of the LONG STRING INSTRUMENT. FULLMAN and WONG will perform their duet Harbors, drawing from soundscapes, stories and atmospheres that manifest around bodies of water.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 13:39:00 +1100</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-long-string-instrument/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-long-string-instrument/</guid>
        
        
        <category>whats-on</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dry land ecology</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;INLAND is a concert series of Australian exploratory music, presenting artists working at the intersection of notated, improvised, electro-acoustic and popular disciplines, and spanning a number of Australian cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over three nights, twelve Australian sound artists will present works mapping a confluence of exploratory streams, tracing a detailed image of contemporary sound practice in Australia today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;featuring-performances-by&quot;&gt;FEATURING PERFORMANCES BY:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WED 28 SEPT:&lt;/strong&gt; Natasha Anderson, Alexander Garsden, Rosalind Hall, Sabina Maselli, Amanda Stewart, Lizzy Welsh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THURS 29 SEPT:&lt;/strong&gt; Hanna Chetwin, Rohan Drape, Rosalind Hall, Francis Plagne, Amanda Stewart, Lizzy Welsh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRI 30 SEPT:&lt;/strong&gt; Alexander Garsden, Paddy Mann, Evelyn Morris, Francis Plagne, Byron Scullin&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 17:37:37 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/inland-concert-series-dry-land-ecology/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/inland-concert-series-dry-land-ecology/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two parts of easy action</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TWO PARTS OF EASY ACTION is a solo work choreographed and performed by DEANNE BUTTERWORTH with critically acclaimed, experimental musician EVELYN MORRIS.  It examines the vulnerability and power of the solo performer using dance and music. Occurring in two parts, one old and one new, DEANNE revisits a work shown at NGV for Melbourne Now in 2014 where she performed with EVELYN in a gallery displaying eighteenth century paintings. The new part is a performance involving a guitar. She is a dancer, not a musician.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of this work, she seeks to unearth a particular performance language using a known and an unfamiliar form. She reinvents the mundane, through exploring repetition in action and sound while conjuring rhythms and undercurrents of energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TWO PARTS OF EASY ACTION is devised for the cavernous SUBSTATION, working with the existing energy of the space to add a dynamic physical and sonic presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-artists&quot;&gt;The Artists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEANNE BUTTERWORTH.&lt;/strong&gt; Performing in the work of dance and other artists, her choreographic practice focuses on collaboration and working in outdoor spaces. Among others she has worked with SHELLEY LASICA, Danceworks Company &amp;amp; Sandra Parker Dance, JO LLOYD, and Phillip Adams BalletLab. Her works have been presented and supported by Dancehouse, Dance New Amsterdam (NYC), Lucy Guerin Inc., Melbourne Fringe, Melbourne Festival, Next Wave Festival, Dance Massive, West Space, Arup, Critical Path and National Gallery of Victoria. In 2012 BUTTERWORTH collaborated with artist LINDA TEGG to create a site specific work at a convenience store. In 2014 BUTTERWORTH performed Regarding Yesterday, by Brussels based choreographer, ADVA ZAKAI. She performed Intermission (MARIA HASSABI) and Defending Plural Experiences, (ALICIA FRANKOVICH), both at ACCA; she also performed Entitled Title, (Keir Choreographic Award). During 2015/16 Deanne performed in Solos For Other People by Lasica (Dance Massive 15); worked with Lasica and JO LLOYD (How Choreography Works, West Space); developed new works with LEE SERLE, SHIAN LAW, TIM DARBYSHIRE, and began two new works- Re-enactments located outdoors, Easy Action a work for dancer and guitar and Interlude for Spring 1883 at The Windsor Hotel. Most recently she performed in work by BELLE BASSIN, (Heide MOMA), and at AGNSW for the Biennale of Sydney Public Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVELYN MORRIS&lt;/strong&gt; has had a musical career with a great deal of variety. Starting out as a punk/thrash drummer in bands such as True Radical Miracle and art-rock group Baseball MORRIS travelled all over the world performing loud and intricate beats. Baseball travelled to Japan, Taiwan, and all over Europe. Whilst there MORRIS met up with DARREN HANLON and continued to tour playing drums and singing with him in Europe - and then for several tours in Australia. Not content with just drums, in amidst all this she started her own musical project called Pikelet. Pikelet has released three full-length albums and several EPs, all received great critical acclaim, and MORRIS travelled around The States and Europe performing. Pikelet has appeared several times at festivals such as Golden Plains, Melbourne International Arts Festival and supported a wide range of international artists such as Sufjan Stevens, Goldfrapp, Devendra Banhart and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014 EVELYN MORRIS was awarded The Age Music Victoria award for best experimental/avant garde act, nominated and voted for by her esteemed peers in the field.  Recently MORRIS started the LISTEN group, a community effort at creating discourse and documenting the history around women’s involvement in music in Australia. This project has created great changes within the musical communities in Melbourne and continues to grow and influence the way music is utilized in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 17:21:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/two-parts-of-easy-action/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/two-parts-of-easy-action/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blowin' up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;BLOWIN’ UP is a series of three linked solo performances from the makers of THIS IS WHAT’S HAPPENING (Winner: Best Dance, 2015 Melbourne Fringe Awards). Contemporary dances that are a bit like performance, and contemporary performances that are a bit like dance, three strange takes on what it feels like to be alive. Alice Dixon, Caroline Meaden and William McBride present BLOWIN’ UP as part of The SUBSTATION’s curated Melbourne Fringe Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In SNEAKY BASTARD Caroline lies in wait. In thick silence and with deep restraint, she plans and then lashes out. Come see the Murky Beauty dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In THE BUSH CAPITAL Alice is off on a journey. Torn between her impulses to either re-join the natural world, or to rule it, follow our heroine as she breaks down walls and faces up to some of life’s greatest hurdles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With LYIN’ DOWN we can all relax. William brings us all together for a natter and a bit of a roll around. Part-storytime, part-awkward lap dance, part-hypnotism, part-requiem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-artists&quot;&gt;ABOUT THE ARTISTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALICE DIXON, CAROLINE MEADEN and WILLIAM MCBRIDE work in a non-hierarchical collaboration as performers and devisers of new unusual contemporary dance-theatre. DIXON and MEADEN have worked together in contemporary dance, performance and film for seven years, with MCBRIDE joining the collaboration in 2013 with a background in theatre, writing and performance installation. Each artist has an established solo practice that complements and extends their collaboration. Their most recent work, THIS IS WHAT’S HAPPENING was presented as part of Darebin Arts’ Speakeasy program for the 2015 Melbourne Fringe. The work was critically acclaimed, won the Melbourne Fringe Award for Best Dance, and has been nominated for an Australian Dance Award for Outstanding Achievement in Independent Dance and a Green Room Award for Best Sound. Their performance work is an enquiry at the intersection of dance and theatre that foregrounds rigorous and unusual physicality, inventive writing and spoken delivery and choreographic performance structures and dramaturgical logics. Their performance works are layer-cakes of form and reference that speak to the complexity of what it feels like to be alive in this ‘heartbroken little era.’ Their work seeks to expand rather than lock-down meaning and embraces multiplicity and complexity over declarations of certitude.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 17:19:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/blowin-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/blowin-up/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Holly Durant</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- https://thesubstation.org.au/show/holly-durant/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working through a series of developments which are centred around the exploration of image construction and meaning while observing the body – I am particularly focusing on how we observe, build and warp meaning of the female body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking at how we can mask, evolve and devolve the body live through choreography and strategising the placement and viewpoints of the observer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am interested in how we can invert the effects of our natural environments – gravity, momentum, space proximity and textures to rebuild meaning and amplify implied and embedded myths, delving into the deep feminine identity and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be exploring both physical and digital manipulation to extrapolate and represent these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/holly-durant/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/holly-durant/</guid>
        
        
        <category>in-development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thembi Soddell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;THEMBI SODDELL will spend three weeks at The SUBSTATION developing a new multi-channel sound installation as part of her practice-led PhD research, which examines how sound might be used to convey firsthand experiences of mental illness and emotional distress. This development period will involve experiments with how listener’s perceive ambiguous and emotionally charged sound material while listening in complete darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-thembi-soddell&quot;&gt;ABOUT THEMBI SODDELL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THEMBI SODDELL (b.1980) is an Australian sound artist, electroacoustic composer and practice-led researcher with an interest in psychology, perception, extreme emotion and the subjectivity of experience. She works primarily with the sampler, generating sounds from field recordings, instrument textures, played found objects and synthesis to form surreal and ambiguous realisations of place and experience. These volatile, filmic sound worlds often exploit the dynamic extremes, toying with a listener’s sense of expectation and disquiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She creates work for recording, installation, live performance and concert presentation. Her CV includes the release of four major composition works for CD; guest curation for the National Gallery of Victoria’s Melbourne Now sound program (Melbourne 2014); works exhibited at the Wellington Art Gallery (Wellington 2013), Parisonic Festival (Paris 2011), National Gallery of Australia (Online 2004) and SFMOMA (San Francisco 2002); solo performances at Australian experimental music festivals such as the Totally Huge New Music Festival (Perth 2009), What Is Music? (Melbourne 2004), Liquid Architecture (Auckland 2006, Sydney 2005, Melbourne 2001); and two European tours in duo with ANTHEA CADDY including performances at the Hörkunstfestival (Erlangen 2006), Biegungen Festival (Berlin 2009) and Instants Chavirés (Paris 2006).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SODDELL has a BA in Media Arts (2002) and first-class honours in Sound Art (2005) from RMIT University, where she is now a PhD candidate. Her research focuses on the articulation of firsthand experiences of mental illness and psychological distress in sound art practice, using sound as a means to provoke thought around issues related to health and emotional wellbeing. She also assisted in running Australian experimental music label, cajid media, has an ongoing duo with cellist, ANTHEA CADDY, and has worked as sound designer and dramaturg for choreographer, TIM DARBYSHIRE.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/thembi-soddell/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/thembi-soddell/</guid>
        
        
        <category>in-development</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
