<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-09-20T14:31:03+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/</id><title type="html">The SUBSTATION</title><subtitle>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</subtitle><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><entry><title type="html">Newport Archives</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Newport Archives" /><published>2007-12-31T12:56:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-12-31T12:56:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/">&lt;p&gt;NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport.  Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newport Archives is available by appointment. Email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@thesubstation.org.au&quot;&gt;info@thesubstation.org.au&lt;/a&gt; to book. Each session runs for 40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio Design by JOE TALIA.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commissioned by The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport. Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/newport-archives-2017.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rabble</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/the-rabble/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rabble" /><published>2007-12-01T10:47:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-12-01T10:47:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/the-rabble</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/the-rabble/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://therabble.com.au/&quot;&gt;THE RABBLE&lt;/a&gt; is developing ULYSSES; an epic, ten-hour contemporary performance inspired by James Joyce’s novel of the same name. THE RABBLE takes our cues from Joyce’s seminal modernist text creating an epic investigation of femininity, death and performance. THE RABBLE’s ULYSSES includes: a woman breast feeding, 309 Questions &amp;amp; 308 Answers, a desperately problematic feminist reading of the narrative events of Ulysses, a meal, a poor theatre version of Hamlet, a slapstick endurance event, a porno, a collective barn dance and a woman saying yes. THE RABBLE are one of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesubstation.org.au/show/the-rabble/&quot;&gt;ARTISTS IN RESIDENCE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">THE RABBLE is developing ULYSSES; an epic, ten-hour contemporary performance inspired by James Joyce’s novel of the same name. THE RABBLE takes our cues from Joyce’s seminal modernist text creating an epic investigation of femininity, death and performance. THE RABBLE’s ULYSSES includes: a woman breast feeding, 309 Questions &amp;amp; 308 Answers, a desperately problematic feminist reading of the narrative events of Ulysses, a meal, a poor theatre version of Hamlet, a slapstick endurance event, a porno, a collective barn dance and a woman saying yes. THE RABBLE are one of our ARTISTS IN RESIDENCE.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/ulyssis.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Claire Edwardes and Richard Cilli</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/claire-edwardes-and-richard-cilli/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Claire Edwardes and Richard Cilli" /><published>2007-12-01T10:46:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-12-01T10:46:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/claire-edwardes-and-richard-cilli</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/claire-edwardes-and-richard-cilli/">&lt;p&gt;Described as the ‘sorceress of percussion’, celebrated Sydney-based percussionist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.claireedwardes.com/&quot;&gt;CLAIRE EDWARDES&lt;/a&gt; unites with Helpmann award-winning dancer and choreographer RICHARD CILLI in a new physically virtuosic work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directed by acclaimed choreographer GIDEON OBARZANEK, two very different artists collide as they are pitted against one another, taking an abrasive look at the things that divide and unite us. Touching on themes including gender, sexuality, psychology and age, EDWARDES and CILLI will take aim at our desire to connect despite our differences.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Described as the ‘sorceress of percussion’, celebrated Sydney-based percussionist CLAIRE EDWARDES unites with Helpmann award-winning dancer and choreographer RICHARD CILLI in a new physically virtuosic work.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/richard.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We Are People – An Exhibition of The Democratic Set</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/we-are-people-an-exhibition-of-the-democratic-set/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Are People – An Exhibition of The Democratic Set" /><published>2007-11-10T10:11:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-11-10T10:11:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/we-are-people-an-exhibition-of-the-democratic-set</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/we-are-people-an-exhibition-of-the-democratic-set/">&lt;p&gt;Over eight years, &lt;a href=&quot;http://backtobacktheatre.com/&quot;&gt;BACK TO BACK THEATRE&lt;/a&gt; has worked with 28 communities to create a series of short films that explore the ideals of equality and freedom. This exhibition captures 12 of these films, each a portrait of a community, exposing their differences and the similarities that connect us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disturbingly obvious and tantalisingly strange, &lt;a href=&quot;http://backtobacktheatre.com/projects/democratic-set/&quot;&gt;THE DEMOCRATIC SET&lt;/a&gt; uses a custom-made film set and a neutral room with two opposing doors. Authoring a unique living snapshot of a community at a particular moment in time, THE DEMOCRATIC SET invites each participant to untangle what an uncensored space means to them, with each viewer surprised and seduced by the mysterious, funny, poignant and provocative sets as they pan the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and BACK TO BACK THEATRE.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Over eight years, BACK TO BACK THEATRE has worked with 28 communities to create a series of short films that explore the ideals of equality and freedom. This exhibition captures 12 of these films, each a portrait of a community, exposing their differences and the similarities that connect us all.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/democratic-set.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tetsuya Umeda</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tetsuya-umeda/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tetsuya Umeda" /><published>2007-10-30T10:10:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-10-30T10:10:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tetsuya-umeda</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tetsuya-umeda/">&lt;p&gt;Based in Osaka, Japan, &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/106567276&quot;&gt;TETSUYA UMEDA&lt;/a&gt; creates dynamic environments through the combination of architectural structures, sound and light. His site-specific and temporal works utilise found domestic objects and transform them from their daily familiarity into a transcendent spectacle of the unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UMEDA’s richly dynamic and embodied installations that are often situated outside of the gallery context, encourage audience members to explore the interaction of its constituent parts, and by doing so, discover their own individuated perceptions, as a part of and in relation to his work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and LIQUID ARCHITECTURE in association with PERFORMANCE SPACE and ROOM40.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Based in Osaka, Japan, TETSUYA UMEDA creates dynamic environments through the combination of architectural structures, sound and light. His site-specific and temporal works utilise found domestic objects and transform them from their daily familiarity into a transcendent spectacle of the unexpected.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/tetsuya.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Plastic Loaves Makes You… Spring</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/plastic-loaves-makes-you-spring/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plastic Loaves Makes You... Spring" /><published>2007-10-20T08:06:00+10:00</published><updated>2007-10-20T08:06:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/plastic-loaves-makes-you-spring</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/plastic-loaves-makes-you-spring/">&lt;p&gt;Spring time has slinked on in and activity is rousingly warmer. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plasticloaves.com/&quot;&gt;PLASTIC LOAVES&lt;/a&gt;’ windows thrust open to invite you inside The SUBSTATION for an evening to flourish together. With each space landscaped and pruned by a certified living artist, the sweet air will excrete all night with a long stem of budding performers, vocals, sounds, visuals and alluring beverages, emerging from every gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With ANDRÁS, LUCY CLICHE (LIVE), MATTHEW BROWN (LIVE), NITE FLEIT, MAGIC STEVEN (LIVE), GIAN MANIK, RUBY JEPPE, BEANIES (TOKYO), DIDVID.S, PRACTISESTUDIOPRACTISE, MIETTA CONVENTRY, CHARLIE FREEDMAN, BRAD &amp;amp; CHAD, BILLIE MORRIS, HYUN LEE, VICTOR BRAVO and WATERFALL PERSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and PLASTIC LOAVES.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Spring time has slinked on in and activity is rousingly warmer. PLASTIC LOAVES’ windows thrust open to invite you inside The SUBSTATION for an evening to flourish together. With each space landscaped and pruned by a certified living artist, the sweet air will excrete all night with a long stem of budding performers, vocals, sounds, visuals and alluring beverages, emerging from every gap.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/plastic-loaves.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">More Up A Tree</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/more-up-a-tree/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="More Up A Tree" /><published>2007-10-12T09:05:00+10:00</published><updated>2007-10-12T09:05:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/more-up-a-tree</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/more-up-a-tree/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/167341682&quot;&gt;MORE UP A TREE&lt;/a&gt; is a performance by drummer &lt;a href=&quot;http://anchorandhope.com/&quot;&gt;JIM WHITE&lt;/a&gt;, dancer CLAUDIA DE SERPA SOARES and artist EVE SUSSMAN, that takes place in a 7 x 4m box of 2-way mirrored Plexiglas. At times the audience sees through the glass but the dancer and drummer cannot see out, and at others, the audience can only see themselves reflected back from the mirrored glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The performers are alone, in public. This unusual sense of privacy changes their demeanor while the audience takes on an ordained voyeurism, transcending the usual performer-viewer relationship. By doing away with narrative and melody, and making a constantly “in flux” relationship to the public, attention is focused on the agency of the drumming and dancing and the audience. MORE UP A TREE reveals the meaningful nature of movement by removing tonality and concentrating action inside a box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">MORE UP A TREE is a performance by drummer JIM WHITE, dancer CLAUDIA DE SERPA SOARES and artist EVE SUSSMAN, that takes place in a 7 x 4m box of 2-way mirrored Plexiglas. At times the audience sees through the glass but the dancer and drummer cannot see out, and at others, the audience can only see themselves reflected back from the mirrored glass.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/muat.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Diomira</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/diomira/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Diomira" /><published>2007-10-07T09:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2007-10-07T09:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/diomira</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/diomira/">&lt;p&gt;Sparked off by one of the imaginary lands in ITALO CALVINO’s novella Invisible Cities, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aao.com.au/&quot;&gt;AUSTRALIAN ART ORCHESTRA&lt;/a&gt;’s DIOMIRA is an expedition forging a path between the observable and the unreal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chamber jazz orchestra expands with the additions of turntables, reel-to-reel tape machines and live signal processing, while the sounds of acoustic instruments and voices are interwoven with vinyl-cut field recordings, toying with perceptions of what is heard and what has only been imagined. This layered sound world is further augmented by multiscreen projections as time folds into itself, leaving the residue of moments half-remembered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring the spaces between the avant-garde and the traditional, art and popular music since 1994, AUSTRALIAN ART ORCHESTRA is fired by the same spirit of restlessness that drove the earliest pioneers of jazz to produce music that defined the twentieth century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Composer: Peter Knight&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Sparked off by one of the imaginary lands in ITALO CALVINO’s novella Invisible Cities, AUSTRALIAN ART ORCHESTRA’s DIOMIRA is an expedition forging a path between the observable and the unreal.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/diomira.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">No New Noise</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/no-new-noise/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="No New Noise" /><published>2007-10-06T08:59:00+10:00</published><updated>2007-10-06T08:59:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/no-new-noise</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/no-new-noise/">&lt;p&gt;In an age of personal assistants hidden inside mobile phones, driverless cars and increasingly self-aware technology, NO NEW NOISE asks the dangerous question: how long until artificial intelligence replaces composers
and musicians?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three composers respond to this provocative inquiry with new works for a powerhouse eight piece improvising ensemble. Exploring questions of authenticity in an age of digital reproduction, JOE O’CONNOR, REUBEN LEWIS, and ALISTAIR MCLEAN investigate the overlap between computers and creativity and ponder the very nature of intelligence in a trio of works that engage and challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NO NEW NOISE is the inaugural program by the AUSTRALIAN CREATIVE MUSIC ENSEMBLE, a new contemporary collective focused on improvising and showcasing the next generation of creative musicians and composers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.festival.melbourne/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">In an age of personal assistants hidden inside mobile phones, driverless cars and increasingly self-aware technology, NO NEW NOISE asks the dangerous question: how long until artificial intelligence replaces composers and musicians?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/no-new-noise.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Exchange Lab</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/exchange-lab/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exchange Lab" /><published>2007-09-29T06:58:00+10:00</published><updated>2007-09-29T06:58:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/exchange-lab</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/exchange-lab/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forestfringe.co.uk/&quot;&gt;FOREST FRINGE&lt;/a&gt; X &lt;a href=&quot;https://melbournefringe.com.au/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE FRINGE&lt;/a&gt; is an innovative residency project bringing together local and international artists to explore the streets and spaces of Melbourne’s West. The project brings award-winning Edinburgh Fringe Festival innovators FOREST FRINGE (UK) to Melbourne for the first time, joining forces with MELBOURNE FRINGE, our own big, bold and gloriously messy celebration of independent art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOREST FRINGE EXCHANGE LAB: DAY OF ACTION 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FRIDAY 29 SEPTEMBER, 10AM - 6PM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.melbournefringe.com.au/event/forest-exchange-lab-day-of-action-2/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOOK NOW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FOREST FRINGE invites you to explore the relationship between artists and the places and spaces where they make their art. After a week of enquiry as part of their residency at the SUBSTATION, join risk-chasers FOREST FRINGE with a group of local artists in Newport for a day of breathless performance making and improvising conclusions to the conundrums they’ve dreamed up. Come ready for adventure and be prepared to head into the unknown.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FOREST FRINGE EXCHANGE LAB: AFTERNOON ASSEMBLY 2&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FRIDAY 29 SEPTEMBER, 5PM&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;FREE&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.melbournefringe.com.au/event/forest-exchange-lab-afternoon-assembly-2/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BOOK NOW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Witness the fruits of a hard day’s performance making in Newport. See what the UK’s FOREST FRINGE along with local artists and their participants have created throughout their Days of Action at The SUBSTATION in an Afternoon Assembly. Come for the showing, stay for a drink and a chat about their discoveries. This art is new, raw, and possibly a little messy – just the way you like it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">FOREST FRINGE X MELBOURNE FRINGE is an innovative residency project bringing together local and international artists to explore the streets and spaces of Melbourne’s West. The project brings award-winning Edinburgh Fringe Festival innovators FOREST FRINGE (UK) to Melbourne for the first time, joining forces with MELBOURNE FRINGE, our own big, bold and gloriously messy celebration of independent art.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/exchange-lab.jpg" /></entry></feed>