<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-27T11:48:31+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The SUBSTATION</title><subtitle>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</subtitle><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><entry><title type="html">CHORUS</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/chorus/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CHORUS" /><published>2018-11-14T11:45:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-11-14T11:45:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/chorus</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/chorus/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-darkly-humorous-look-at-the-social-function-of-gossip-&quot;&gt;A DARKLY HUMOROUS LOOK AT THE SOCIAL FUNCTION OF GOSSIP. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CHORUS explores Greek mythology through an immersive multiscreen and sound installation. Drawing its title from the group of performers in Greek theatre whose role it is to comment on the action, this darkly humorous work invites visitors to think about the role of gossip in culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the videos performance artist Melanie Jame Wolf’s inhabits a series of electrifying personas from ancient Greek mythology. These female deities – representing virtues and ideas ranging from love, beauty, wisdom to chaos – are inhabited by the artist with camp abandon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using overlapping speech and sound and theatrical visual techniques to create a cacophonous soundscape, CHORUS embraces flamboyance, theatricality and a joyfully pop sensibility while exploring serious questions about Western civilisation. How do we interpret and report on human behaviour? In what way do our voices – in unison – enforce cultural attitudes? How does gossip enforce notions of properness and shame?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.savage-amusement.com/about-savage-amusement&quot;&gt;Melanie Jame Wolf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is an Australian born artist who lives and works between Melbourne and Berlin. She makes work about economies. Sometimes solo, sometimes with friends. Always exploring systems of value and exchange, particularly as they occur in the murky field of immaterial capital – the social, the cultural, the affective. She investigates these flows as they are produced through ideas of ghosts, of gender, of pop, of myth, of morality, of sensuality, of class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">A DARKLY HUMOROUS LOOK AT THE SOCIAL FUNCTION OF GOSSIP.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Chorus.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">WILLIAM BASINSKI  CATERINA BARBIERI</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/william-basinski-caterina-barbieri/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="WILLIAM BASINSKI 
CATERINA BARBIERI" /><published>2018-11-07T12:06:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-11-07T12:06:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/william-basinski-caterina-barbieri</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/william-basinski-caterina-barbieri/">&lt;p&gt;A SONIC JOURNEY INTO HAUNTING AND MESMERISING SOUNDSCAPES.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join two renowned international composers on a haunting and mesmerising sonic journey. New York based, composer and musician William Basinski performs his only Australian solo performance in a double bill with Berlin-based Italian composer Caterina Barbieri in her first live performance in Australia following appearances at prestigious festivals Berlin Atonal and Unsound (Krakow). These two giants of experimental sound create hypnotic sonic experiences – minimal, mysterious and meditative – using synthesizers and obsolete analogue technologies that will expand your sense of time, space and self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uzcHdxTj00I&quot;&gt;William Basinski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a classically trained musician and composer who has been working in experimental media for over 30 years in NYC and most recently, California. Employing obsolete technology and analogue tape loops, his haunting and melancholy soundscapes explore the temporal nature of life and resound with the reverberations of memory and the mystery of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x4aH1HGzCUc&quot;&gt;Caterina Barbieri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is an Italian composer now based in Berlin. Repetition and pattern permutation lie at the core of her current sonic research. She has composed music for old and new synthesizers as well as for string instruments. By means of synthesis, pattern-based operations and additive canons, her music draws severe geometries in time and space. Her work explores themes of machine intelligence and object-oriented perception in sound through approaching music practice as an integrative cognitive feedback between humans and technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">A SONIC JOURNEY INTO HAUNTING AND MESMERISING SOUNDSCAPES.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/WB.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Hi-Viz Practice Exchange</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/hi-viz-practice-exchange/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hi-Viz Practice Exchange" /><published>2018-11-05T11:28:00+11:00</published><updated>2018-11-05T11:28:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/hi-viz-practice-exchange</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/hi-viz-practice-exchange/">&lt;p&gt;Hi-Viz Practice Exchange is a new Chamber Made initiative for women working across performance, sound and music. It’s is a day of discussions, exchanges, and interactions aimed at deepening dialogue around cross-artform practice. Hi-Viz is for everyone in this space, from emerging to established artists. Hi-Viz is designed to bring women performance-makers, directors, composers, and sound artists into conversation with one another. The practice exchange is intended to deepen dialogue, build networks, and nurture new understandings between women performance makers, theatre directors, composers, and sound artists.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Hi-Viz Practice Exchange is a new Chamber Made initiative for women working across performance, sound and music. It’s is a day of discussions, exchanges, and interactions aimed at deepening dialogue around cross-artform practice. Hi-Viz is for everyone in this space, from emerging to established artists. Hi-Viz is designed to bring women performance-makers, directors, composers, and sound artists into conversation with one another. The practice exchange is intended to deepen dialogue, build networks, and nurture new understandings between women performance makers, theatre directors, composers, and sound artists.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Hivis.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Charlemagne Palestine</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/charlemagne-palestine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Charlemagne Palestine" /><published>2018-06-23T08:14:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-06-23T08:14:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/charlemagne-palestine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/charlemagne-palestine/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/music/2010/mar/04/charlemagne-palestine-carillon-bells&quot;&gt;CHARLEMAGNE PALESTINE&lt;/a&gt; is a critically acclaimed artist exploring the transcendent potentials of music. Working across questions of resonance and duration, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bulibjyaQ0s&amp;amp;t=1247s&quot;&gt;PALESTINE&lt;/a&gt;’s works for piano, organ, carillon and voice are defining moments in the 20th and 21st Century, exploring states of trace realised through music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His work with organ specifically has created some of the most harmonically rich and intense explorations for that instrument. PALESTINE will deliver a powerful performance for organ and voice on the historic organ of the Holy Trinity Anglican Church, Williamstown, working with the architecture of the space to explore harmony, overtones and the very resonance of music itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION in association with &lt;a href=&quot;http://room40.org/&quot;&gt;ROOM40&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">CHARLEMAGNE PALESTINE is a critically acclaimed artist exploring the transcendent potentials of music. Working across questions of resonance and duration, PALESTINE’s works for piano, organ, carillon and voice are defining moments in the 20th and 21st Century, exploring states of trace realised through music.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/charlemagne-palestine.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bunker</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/bunker/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bunker" /><published>2018-06-15T10:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-06-15T10:20:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/bunker</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/bunker/">&lt;p&gt;Expect the very best in techno as &lt;a href=&quot;http://bunker-music.com/&quot;&gt;BUNKER&lt;/a&gt; returns to The SUBSTATION for a third year to celebrate their fifth Birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining the celebrations will be two international guests Ansome (Live) (S.L.A.M / MORD / Perc Trax, UK) and Stephanie Sykes (47 / Full Panda, UK).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local support from DJ Kiti b2b Nite Fleit, ACM (Live) &amp;amp; Concealed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and BUNKER.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Expect the very best in techno as BUNKER returns to The SUBSTATION for a third year to celebrate their fifth Birthday.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/bunker-2018.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">BIN DIXON-WARD</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bin-dixon-ward/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BIN DIXON-WARD" /><published>2018-06-12T14:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-06-12T14:40:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bin-dixon-ward</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bin-dixon-ward/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;bin.dixon-ward.com&quot;&gt;BIN DIXON-WARD&lt;/a&gt;’s work uses 3D printing to explore the links between the geometry of urban and industrial infrastructure across the West through contemporary jewellery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Melbourne’s sparkling CBD towers in the rearview mirror, the West Gate freeway is an artery through rapidly changing industrial and suburban landscapes. ‘This is what’s left of the West Gate’ examines the region by drawing upon satellite images to reveal a not just a landscape featuring the massive infrastructure of industrial and manufacturing industries but coastal wetlands, housing, parklands and sports fields, shipping and cleared ‘ghost sites’, evidence of past industrial histories, all laid out along a lacelike network of creeks, roads and railways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BIN DIXON-WARD’s jewellery reflects the impact of the changing role of the western suburbs using technologies of the ‘next industrial age’. Using the same tools that are used to design cities, and buildings to design jewellery but on a micro scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and The &lt;a href=&quot;artandindustryfestival.com.au&quot;&gt;ART &amp;amp; INDUSTRY FESTIVAL.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">BIN DIXON-WARD’s work uses 3D printing to explore the links between the geometry of urban and industrial infrastructure across the West through contemporary jewellery.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Bin-Dixon-Ward.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kim Myhr with the AAO and Tony Buck</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/kim-myhr-norway-with-the-aao/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kim Myhr with the AAO and Tony Buck" /><published>2018-06-09T08:08:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-06-09T08:08:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/kim-myhr-norway-with-the-aao</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/kim-myhr-norway-with-the-aao/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kimmyhr.com/&quot;&gt;KIM MYHR&lt;/a&gt; takes to the stage with one of Australia’s most distinctive and adventurous contemporary music ensembles the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aao.com.au/&quot;&gt;AUSTRALIAN ART ORCHESTRA&lt;/a&gt;, performing the world premiere of a work he created especially for the shape-shifting 10-piece orchestra. Two violinists, two drummers, bass, hammered dulcimer, electronics, bass clarinet, Revox reel-to-reel tape machine and Myhr’s 12-string electric guitar make up the unusual sonic union.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Award-winning young bass clarinet virtuoso, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.avivaendean.com/&quot;&gt;AVIVA ENDEAN&lt;/a&gt;, incendiary violinist &lt;a href=&quot;http://erkkiveltheim.com/&quot;&gt;ERKKI VELTHEIM&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tony-buck.com/&quot;&gt;TONY BUCK&lt;/a&gt; and PETER KNIGHT are amongst the musician line-up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kim Myhr, guitar &lt;br /&gt;
Peter Knight, trumpet, electronics &lt;br /&gt; 
Aviva Endean, bass clarinet &lt;br /&gt;
Tony Buck drum kit &lt;br /&gt;
Lizzy Welsh, violin &lt;br /&gt;
Erkki Veltheim, violin &lt;br /&gt;
Jacques Emery, contra bass, hammered dulcimer &lt;br /&gt;
Joe Talia, Revox B77 reel-to-reel tape machine, percussion &lt;br /&gt;
Jem Savage, sound design, live sound  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://melbournejazz.com/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE INTERNATIONAL JAZZ FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AUSTRALIAN ART ORCHESTRA is assisted by the Australian Government through the Australia Council, its arts funding and advisory body.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">KIM MYHR takes to the stage with one of Australia’s most distinctive and adventurous contemporary music ensembles the AUSTRALIAN ART ORCHESTRA, performing the world premiere of a work he created especially for the shape-shifting 10-piece orchestra. Two violinists, two drummers, bass, hammered dulcimer, electronics, bass clarinet, Revox reel-to-reel tape machine and Myhr’s 12-string electric guitar make up the unusual sonic union.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/kim-myhr-8.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">THREE SOLOS</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/kim-myhr/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="THREE SOLOS" /><published>2018-06-08T01:57:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-06-08T01:57:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/kim-myhr</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/kim-myhr/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kimmyhr.com/&quot;&gt;KIM MYHR&lt;/a&gt; 12 string guitar &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kim Myhr’s solo performances are hypnotic. At once virtuosic and gestural, the sound world slowly unfolds as harmonics are gradually shifted through minute changes to a continuous strumming pattern. His performances have been described as “an orchestral exploration of the 12-string guitar sounding like something in between American folk strumming and 60s avant-garde soundness orchestral music.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=phFRdRN-H1A&quot;&gt;LISTEN
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tony-buck.com/&quot;&gt;TONY BUCK&lt;/a&gt; drums and guitar &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tony Buck is one of the most extraordinary musicians Australia has produced. Based in Berlin for over two decades he has made his fame with iconic group, The Necks, which was recently called “the greatest trio on earth” by the New York Times. This concert will present a very rare solo performance by Tony Buck, who has been developing a performance mode that involves drum kit and electric guitar. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HW6d6DnWiJ0&quot;&gt;WATCH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://peterknightmusic.com/&quot;&gt;PETER KNIGHT&lt;/a&gt; trumpet, Revox B77 reel-to-reel, laptop &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the world premiere live performance of a new piece Peter Knight has created for processed trumpet. Solo for Trumpet, Delays, Tape Loops, and Rice, showcases Peter’s unique approach to the instrument which uses laptop computer, Revox reel-to-reel tape, dropping rice, and multiple speakers to create an immersive experience. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WStrnakAJIE&quot;&gt;WATCH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://melbournejazz.com/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE INTERNATIONAL JAZZ FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">KIM MYHR 12 string guitar</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Three-Solos.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apokalypsis</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/apokalypsis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apokalypsis" /><published>2018-05-15T15:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-15T15:38:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/apokalypsis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/apokalypsis/">&lt;p&gt;While the world spews forth an unrelenting stream of doom and despair, Apokalypsis sees four performers take on the task of presenting 100 historical disasters in 60 minutes. Beginning with the Big Bang and hurtling through a quick-fire stream of events that have edged us into the Anthropocene, this theatrical flip-book presents a narrative of the world as one of repeated annihilation and renewal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As history speeds towards the present day and energy and resources diminish, what emerges is a hallucinogenic vision of a world on the brink of collapse, and a searing indictment of denialism at this extraordinary moment in Earth’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/Apokalypsis%20Program.pdf&quot;&gt;Download the program (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/uploads/Apokalypsis%20Program_Accessibility%20.docx&quot;&gt;Download the program (Word)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performers &amp;amp; Co-Creators: Charles Purcell, Kai Bradley, Marcus McKenzie, Rosie Clynes &lt;br /&gt;
Sound Design &amp;amp; Co-Creator: Zak Pidd &lt;br /&gt;
Set &amp;amp; Costume Design: Jonathan Hindmarsh &lt;br /&gt;
Lighting Design: Katie Sfetkidis &lt;br /&gt;
Lighting Assistant: Nick Moloney (on internship from the Faculty of VCA and Music, Production Course) &lt;br /&gt;
Dramaturgy: Katy Maudlin &lt;br /&gt;
Stage Manager: Tonie-Rayne Steele &lt;br /&gt;
Assistant Stage Manager: Thomas Crawford &lt;br /&gt;
Producer: Natasha Phillips &lt;br /&gt;
Associate Producer: Bron Belcher &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APOKALYPSIS is presented by The SUBSTATION and has been commissioned and developed through Next Wave’s flagship learning program Kickstart Helix. The project is supported by the Victorian Government through Creative Victoria, The Seaborn, Broughton and Walford Foundation, Silvia &amp;amp; Michael Kantor and The Besen Family Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">While the world spews forth an unrelenting stream of doom and despair, Apokalypsis sees four performers take on the task of presenting 100 historical disasters in 60 minutes. Beginning with the Big Bang and hurtling through a quick-fire stream of events that have edged us into the Anthropocene, this theatrical flip-book presents a narrative of the world as one of repeated annihilation and renewal.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/apokalypsis.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Newport Archives</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Newport Archives" /><published>2018-05-12T12:56:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-12T12:56:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/">&lt;p&gt;NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport.  Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newport Archives is available by appointment. Email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@thesubstation.org.au&quot;&gt;info@thesubstation.org.au&lt;/a&gt; to book. Each session runs for 40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio Design by JOE TALIA.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commissioned by The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport. Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/newport-archives-2017.jpg" /></entry></feed>