<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-03T16:50:50+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/</id><title type="html">The SUBSTATION</title><subtitle>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</subtitle><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><entry><title type="html">DREW MCDOWALL</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/drew-mcdowall/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DREW MCDOWALL" /><published>2018-05-01T20:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2018-05-01T20:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/drew%20mcdowall</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/drew-mcdowall/">&lt;p&gt;DREW MCDOWALL is best known as an influential force behind legendary bands COIL and PSYCHIC TV. As the last living member of COIL, Drew performs TIME MACHINES, one of the most influential drone works of the last 20 years. Supported by vocalist and artist KUSUM NORMOYLE who takes screaming, resonance and feedback and puts them to work in the gallery, and for experimental and dance music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION in association with Room40&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">DREW MCDOWALL is best known as an influential force behind legendary bands COIL and PSYCHIC TV. As the last living member of COIL, Drew performs TIME MACHINES, one of the most influential drone works of the last 20 years. Supported by vocalist and artist KUSUM NORMOYLE who takes screaming, resonance and feedback and puts them to work in the gallery, and for experimental and dance music.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/%5B%22/uploads/Drew%20McDowall_Atonal%202016.jpg%22%5D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Newport Archives</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Newport Archives" /><published>2008-12-31T12:56:00+11:00</published><updated>2008-12-31T12:56:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/">&lt;p&gt;NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport.  Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newport Archives is available by appointment. Email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@thesubstation.org.au&quot;&gt;info@thesubstation.org.au&lt;/a&gt; to book. Each session runs for 40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio Design by JOE TALIA.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commissioned by The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport. Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/newport-archives-2017.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Charlemagne Palestine</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/charlemagne-palestine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Charlemagne Palestine" /><published>2008-06-23T13:14:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-06-23T13:14:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/charlemagne-palestine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/charlemagne-palestine/">&lt;p&gt;HOLY TRINITY ANGLICAN CHURCH &lt;br /&gt;
2 PASCO STREET, WILLIAMSTOWN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/music/2010/mar/04/charlemagne-palestine-carillon-bells&quot;&gt;CHARLEMAGNE PALESTINE&lt;/a&gt; is a critically acclaimed artist exploring the transcendent potentials of music. Working across questions of resonance and duration, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bulibjyaQ0s&amp;amp;t=1247s&quot;&gt;PALESTINE&lt;/a&gt;’s works for piano, organ, carillon and voice are defining moments in the 20th and 21st Century, exploring states of trace realised through music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His work with organ specifically has created some of the most harmonically rich and intense explorations for that instrument. PALESTINE will deliver a powerful performance for organ and voice on the historic organ of the Holy Trinity Anglican Church, Williamstown, working with the architecture of the space to explore harmony, overtones and the very resonance of music itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION in association with &lt;a href=&quot;http://room40.org/&quot;&gt;ROOM40&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">HOLY TRINITY ANGLICAN CHURCH 2 PASCO STREET, WILLIAMSTOWN</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/charlemagne-palestine.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bunker</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bunker/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bunker" /><published>2008-06-15T11:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-06-15T11:20:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bunker</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bunker/">&lt;p&gt;Expect the very best in techno as &lt;a href=&quot;http://bunker-music.com/&quot;&gt;BUNKER&lt;/a&gt; returns to The SUBSTATION for a third year to celebrate their fifth Birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining the celebrations will be two international guests Ansome (Live) (S.L.A.M / MORD / Perc Trax, UK) and Stephanie Sykes (47 / Full Panda, UK).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local support from DJ Kiti b2b Nite Fleit, ACM (Live) &amp;amp; Concealed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and BUNKER.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Expect the very best in techno as BUNKER returns to The SUBSTATION for a third year to celebrate their fifth Birthday.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/bunker-2018.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kim Myhr with the AAO</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-norway-with-the-aao/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kim Myhr with the AAO" /><published>2008-06-09T12:08:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-06-09T12:08:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-norway-with-the-aao</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-norway-with-the-aao/">&lt;p&gt;Leading light on the Norwegian experimental scene, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kimmyhr.com/&quot;&gt;KIM MYHR&lt;/a&gt;, performs in the world premiere of a new piece created especially for the shape-shifting 10-piece, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aao.com.au/&quot;&gt;AUSTRALIAN ART ORCHESTRA&lt;/a&gt;. Tailored to the group’s ability to traverse acoustic and electronic textures, MYHR weaves a complex interplay of rhythmic pulses, visceral texture and near psychedelic harmonic density.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KIM MYHR has an established reputation as one of the industries leading contemporary innovators, creating arresting compositions for chamber ensembles, electroacoustic settings and various theatrical projects. These include, most recently, MURAL, with INGAR ZACH and Australian saxophone icon JIM DENLEY, and CIRCADIA with DAVID STACKENÄS, JOE WILLIAMSON, and THE NECKS’ drummer TONY BUCK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://melbournejazz.com/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE INTERNATIONAL JAZZ FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Australian Art Orchestra is assisted by the Australian Government through the Australia Council, its arts funding and advisory body.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Leading light on the Norwegian experimental scene, KIM MYHR, performs in the world premiere of a new piece created especially for the shape-shifting 10-piece, the AUSTRALIAN ART ORCHESTRA. Tailored to the group’s ability to traverse acoustic and electronic textures, MYHR weaves a complex interplay of rhythmic pulses, visceral texture and near psychedelic harmonic density.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/kim-myhr-8.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">KIM MYHR - SOLO WITH PETER KNIGHT</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-solo-norway/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KIM MYHR - SOLO WITH PETER KNIGHT" /><published>2008-06-08T11:57:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-06-08T11:57:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-solo-norway</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-solo-norway/">&lt;p&gt;One of the world’s most distinctive guitarists, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kimmyhr.com/&quot;&gt;KIM MYHR&lt;/a&gt;’s sound has been described as somewhere between American folk strumming and 60s avant-garde orchestral soundmass. For the first time in Australia, KIM MYHR performs redefining solo works for the 12 string guitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MYHR has performed solo at some of the most significant festivals and venues in Europe, establishing his reputation as one of the instrument’s leading contemporary innovators. The WIRE called MYHR’s first release, ALL YOUR LIMBS SINGING (SOFA) as “a delirious love letter to the 12-string guitar.” And in 2016, MYHR released a collaborative album with JENNY HVAL and TRONDHEIM JAZZ ORCHESTRA, “IN THE END HIS VOICE WILL BE THE SOUND OF PAPER” which was described as “…a grotesquely beautiful paradox of sound, pleasing to the last.” – Slug Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MYHR will be joined by trail-blazing trumpeter and sound artist, PETER KNIGHT with a performance of ALLOTROPE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALLOTROPE, that is, the varying atomic states of a physical form (Carbon; Graphite, Diamond) is KNIGHT’s solo piece created using trumpet, laptop electronics, amplifier and pedals. ALLOTROPE explores KNIGHT’s multidisciplinary preoccupation with space, understatement and long form structure, which draws inspiration from a diverse range of sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://peterknightmusic.com/&quot;&gt;PETER KNIGHT&lt;/a&gt;, who has been described as, “Hard to categorise… hauntingly memorable” (The Wire, UK) has toured as a solo artist to major festivals and venues around the world,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If trumpet is an element, then Knight is an alchemist” – New York City Jazz Record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://melbournejazz.com/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE INTERNATIONAL JAZZ FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">One of the world’s most distinctive guitarists, KIM MYHR’s sound has been described as somewhere between American folk strumming and 60s avant-garde orchestral soundmass. For the first time in Australia, KIM MYHR performs redefining solo works for the 12 string guitar.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/kim-myhr-9.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apokalypsis</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/apokalypsis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apokalypsis" /><published>2008-05-15T18:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-05-15T18:38:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/apokalypsis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/apokalypsis/">&lt;p&gt;While the world spews forth an unrelenting stream of doom and despair, Apokalypsis sees four performers take on the task of presenting 100 historical disasters in 60 minutes. Beginning with the Big Bang and hurtling through a quick-fire stream of events that have edged us into the Anthropocene, this theatrical flip-book presents a narrative of the world as one of repeated annihilation and renewal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As history speeds towards the present day and energy and resources diminish, what emerges is a hallucinogenic vision of a world on the brink of collapse, and a searing indictment of denialism at this extraordinary moment in Earth’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Performers &amp;amp; Co-Creators: Charles Purcell, Kai Bradley, Marcus McKenzie, Rosie Clynes &lt;br /&gt;
Sound Design &amp;amp; Co-Creator: Zak Pidd &lt;br /&gt;
Set &amp;amp; Costume Design: Jonathan Hindmarsh &lt;br /&gt;
Lighting Design: Katie Sfetkidis &lt;br /&gt;
Lighting Assistant: Nick Moloney (on internship from the Faculty of VCA and Music, Production Course) &lt;br /&gt;
Dramaturgy: Katy Maudlin &lt;br /&gt;
Stage Manager: Tonie-Rayne Steele &lt;br /&gt;
Assistant Stage Manager: Thomas Crawford &lt;br /&gt;
Producer: Natasha Phillips &lt;br /&gt;
Associate Producer: Bron Belcher &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APOKALYPSIS is presented by The SUBSTATION and has been commissioned and developed through Next Wave’s flagship learning program Kickstart Helix. The project is supported by the Victorian Government through Creative Victoria, The Seaborn, Broughton and Walford Foundation, Silvia &amp;amp; Michael Kantor and The Besen Family Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">While the world spews forth an unrelenting stream of doom and despair, Apokalypsis sees four performers take on the task of presenting 100 historical disasters in 60 minutes. Beginning with the Big Bang and hurtling through a quick-fire stream of events that have edged us into the Anthropocene, this theatrical flip-book presents a narrative of the world as one of repeated annihilation and renewal.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/apokalypsis.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lady Example</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/lady-example/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lady Example" /><published>2008-05-09T02:51:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-05-09T02:51:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/lady-example</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/lady-example/">&lt;p&gt;LADY EXAMPLE is a dance – of bodies, words, and women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created and performed by Alice Dixon, Caroline Meaden and William McBride, with an ensemble of artists, Lady Example undertakes a deranged and exquisite stocktake of our histories and mythologies to propose a litany of new, glorious, shuddering worlds. Combining contemporary dance, text and theatre, this tender and sly performance considers the historical and contemporary feminine – on our stages, on our screens, and in the performance of everyday life – looking at the lady examples that made us, and the lady examples we are making still.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choreography: Alice Dixon, William McBride and Caroline Meaden
Performed by Fleur Conlon, Alice Dixon, Patrick Durnan Silva, Benjamin Hurley, William McBride, Caroline Meaden, Hannah Monson, Emma Riches and Joanne White &lt;br /&gt;
Sound Design: Emah Fox &lt;br /&gt;
Lighting Design: Jason Crick &lt;br /&gt;
Set and Costume Design: Matilda Woodroofe &lt;br /&gt;
Produced: Erin Milne &lt;br /&gt;
Image: Mischa Baka &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by THE SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;http://nextwave.org.au/&quot;&gt;NEXT WAVE&lt;/a&gt;. Supported by City of Melbourne through the Boyd Studio, Creative Victoria, Besen Family Foundation, Creative Partnerships Australia and the Australian Government through Australia Council, its arts funding and advisory body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content warning: contains nudity and strobe effects.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">LADY EXAMPLE is a dance – of bodies, words, and women.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/lady-example-2018.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tracing Transcendence</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tracing-trancendence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tracing Transcendence" /><published>2008-05-04T06:49:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-05-04T06:49:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tracing-trancendence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tracing-trancendence/">&lt;p&gt;Look beyond the cities and the headlines and you’ll see that Islam isn’t new in Australia. Tracing back to the mid-1800s, the presence of Islamic cameleers or “Ghans” in outback Australia led to more than just train tracks and the supply of goods across arid rural terrain – the sacred sites and prayer spaces they left behind tell stories that resonate today in contemporary Muslim Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guided by a strong sense of discipline and tradition, &lt;a href=&quot;http://shireentaweel.com/&quot;&gt;SHIREEN TAWEEL’S&lt;/a&gt; installation of copper, light and sound charts the history of the country’s mosques. Inspired by remote Australian landscapes and Islamic decorative arts, Taweel’s approach is rooted in cross-cultural dialogue and consideration of sacred and secular spaces. The resulting work is a delicate and meditative intersection of past, present and future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PUBLIC PROGRAM&lt;/strong&gt; – From Here Onwards &lt;br /&gt;
SATURDAY 12 May, 1pm – 2pm &lt;br /&gt;
Artist-led Panel discussion unpacking representations in greater Australia, ideas of local histories, fluid identities and transformations from cultural exchange.&lt;br /&gt;
Speakers : Hayley Millar-Baker, Phuong Ngo, Tamara Saulwick and Shireen Taweel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IFTAR FEAST FOR RAMADAN &lt;br /&gt;
THURSDAY 17 May, 5.45pm – 7.00pm &lt;br /&gt;
Food and artists performances in the gallery during the sacred time of Ramadan. Celebrate collective of communities in the west with the simple act of a shared meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and Next Wave, tracing transcendence has been assisted by Create NSW, Anchor Ceramics and the Australian Government through Australia Council, its arts funding and advisory body.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Look beyond the cities and the headlines and you’ll see that Islam isn’t new in Australia. Tracing back to the mid-1800s, the presence of Islamic cameleers or “Ghans” in outback Australia led to more than just train tracks and the supply of goods across arid rural terrain – the sacred sites and prayer spaces they left behind tell stories that resonate today in contemporary Muslim Australia.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/shireen.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">You’re Standing in it</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/youre-standing-in-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You're Standing in it" /><published>2008-05-01T14:33:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-05-01T14:33:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/youre-standing-in-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/youre-standing-in-it/">&lt;p&gt;Resident Artist AMANDA CARR explores the relationship between the observer and environment through an unlikely symbiosis of theatrical staging and liquid mechanics on The SUBSTATION billboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the work, YOU’RE STANDING IN IT, &lt;a href=&quot;http://amandacarrcreative.com/&quot;&gt;AMANDA CARR&lt;/a&gt; forces fluids into a microscopic void between parallel planes to observe the instability produced by differing surface tensions. This phenomenon, known as Hele-Shaw flow, produces a visual landscape that is as foreign as it is familiar, imaginary in appearance yet undeniably natural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CARR’s artistic practice transfers the image onto fabric to craft wearable designs, distorting scale and distinction between background and foreground. The human illusion of autonomy enveloped in a volatile terrain forged through a collision of opposing forces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where does the body end and the environment begin? Do we create each other? Or destroy one another?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Resident Artist AMANDA CARR explores the relationship between the observer and environment through an unlikely symbiosis of theatrical staging and liquid mechanics on The SUBSTATION billboards.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/amanda.jpg" /></entry></feed>