<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The SUBSTATION</title>
    <description>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</description>
    <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 13:12:22 +1100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 13:12:22 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dry land ecology</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;INLAND is a concert series of Australian exploratory music, presenting artists working at the intersection of notated, improvised, electro-acoustic and popular disciplines, and spanning a number of Australian cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over three nights, twelve Australian sound artists will present works mapping a confluence of exploratory streams, tracing a detailed image of contemporary sound practice in Australia today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;featuring-performances-by&quot;&gt;FEATURING PERFORMANCES BY:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WED 28 SEPT:&lt;/strong&gt; Natasha Anderson, Alexander Garsden, Rosalind Hall, Sabina Maselli, Amanda Stewart, Lizzy Welsh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THURS 29 SEPT:&lt;/strong&gt; Hanna Chetwin, Rohan Drape, Rosalind Hall, Francis Plagne, Amanda Stewart, Lizzy Welsh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRI 30 SEPT:&lt;/strong&gt; Alexander Garsden, Paddy Mann, Evelyn Morris, Francis Plagne, Byron Scullin&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 17:37:37 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/inland-concert-series-dry-land-ecology/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/inland-concert-series-dry-land-ecology/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two parts of easy action</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TWO PARTS OF EASY ACTION is a solo work choreographed and performed by DEANNE BUTTERWORTH with critically acclaimed, experimental musician EVELYN MORRIS.  It examines the vulnerability and power of the solo performer using dance and music. Occurring in two parts, one old and one new, DEANNE revisits a work shown at NGV for Melbourne Now in 2014 where she performed with EVELYN in a gallery displaying eighteenth century paintings. The new part is a performance involving a guitar. She is a dancer, not a musician.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of this work, she seeks to unearth a particular performance language using a known and an unfamiliar form. She reinvents the mundane, through exploring repetition in action and sound while conjuring rhythms and undercurrents of energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TWO PARTS OF EASY ACTION is devised for the cavernous SUBSTATION, working with the existing energy of the space to add a dynamic physical and sonic presence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-artists&quot;&gt;The Artists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEANNE BUTTERWORTH.&lt;/strong&gt; Performing in the work of dance and other artists, her choreographic practice focuses on collaboration and working in outdoor spaces. Among others she has worked with SHELLEY LASICA, Danceworks Company &amp;amp; Sandra Parker Dance, JO LLOYD, and Phillip Adams BalletLab. Her works have been presented and supported by Dancehouse, Dance New Amsterdam (NYC), Lucy Guerin Inc., Melbourne Fringe, Melbourne Festival, Next Wave Festival, Dance Massive, West Space, Arup, Critical Path and National Gallery of Victoria. In 2012 BUTTERWORTH collaborated with artist LINDA TEGG to create a site specific work at a convenience store. In 2014 BUTTERWORTH performed Regarding Yesterday, by Brussels based choreographer, ADVA ZAKAI. She performed Intermission (MARIA HASSABI) and Defending Plural Experiences, (ALICIA FRANKOVICH), both at ACCA; she also performed Entitled Title, (Keir Choreographic Award). During 2015/16 Deanne performed in Solos For Other People by Lasica (Dance Massive 15); worked with Lasica and JO LLOYD (How Choreography Works, West Space); developed new works with LEE SERLE, SHIAN LAW, TIM DARBYSHIRE, and began two new works- Re-enactments located outdoors, Easy Action a work for dancer and guitar and Interlude for Spring 1883 at The Windsor Hotel. Most recently she performed in work by BELLE BASSIN, (Heide MOMA), and at AGNSW for the Biennale of Sydney Public Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EVELYN MORRIS&lt;/strong&gt; has had a musical career with a great deal of variety. Starting out as a punk/thrash drummer in bands such as True Radical Miracle and art-rock group Baseball MORRIS travelled all over the world performing loud and intricate beats. Baseball travelled to Japan, Taiwan, and all over Europe. Whilst there MORRIS met up with DARREN HANLON and continued to tour playing drums and singing with him in Europe - and then for several tours in Australia. Not content with just drums, in amidst all this she started her own musical project called Pikelet. Pikelet has released three full-length albums and several EPs, all received great critical acclaim, and MORRIS travelled around The States and Europe performing. Pikelet has appeared several times at festivals such as Golden Plains, Melbourne International Arts Festival and supported a wide range of international artists such as Sufjan Stevens, Goldfrapp, Devendra Banhart and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014 EVELYN MORRIS was awarded The Age Music Victoria award for best experimental/avant garde act, nominated and voted for by her esteemed peers in the field.  Recently MORRIS started the LISTEN group, a community effort at creating discourse and documenting the history around women’s involvement in music in Australia. This project has created great changes within the musical communities in Melbourne and continues to grow and influence the way music is utilized in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 17:21:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/two-parts-of-easy-action/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/two-parts-of-easy-action/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blowin' up</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;BLOWIN’ UP is a series of three linked solo performances from the makers of THIS IS WHAT’S HAPPENING (Winner: Best Dance, 2015 Melbourne Fringe Awards). Contemporary dances that are a bit like performance, and contemporary performances that are a bit like dance, three strange takes on what it feels like to be alive. Alice Dixon, Caroline Meaden and William McBride present BLOWIN’ UP as part of The SUBSTATION’s curated Melbourne Fringe Program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In SNEAKY BASTARD Caroline lies in wait. In thick silence and with deep restraint, she plans and then lashes out. Come see the Murky Beauty dance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In THE BUSH CAPITAL Alice is off on a journey. Torn between her impulses to either re-join the natural world, or to rule it, follow our heroine as she breaks down walls and faces up to some of life’s greatest hurdles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With LYIN’ DOWN we can all relax. William brings us all together for a natter and a bit of a roll around. Part-storytime, part-awkward lap dance, part-hypnotism, part-requiem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-artists&quot;&gt;ABOUT THE ARTISTS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALICE DIXON, CAROLINE MEADEN and WILLIAM MCBRIDE work in a non-hierarchical collaboration as performers and devisers of new unusual contemporary dance-theatre. DIXON and MEADEN have worked together in contemporary dance, performance and film for seven years, with MCBRIDE joining the collaboration in 2013 with a background in theatre, writing and performance installation. Each artist has an established solo practice that complements and extends their collaboration. Their most recent work, THIS IS WHAT’S HAPPENING was presented as part of Darebin Arts’ Speakeasy program for the 2015 Melbourne Fringe. The work was critically acclaimed, won the Melbourne Fringe Award for Best Dance, and has been nominated for an Australian Dance Award for Outstanding Achievement in Independent Dance and a Green Room Award for Best Sound. Their performance work is an enquiry at the intersection of dance and theatre that foregrounds rigorous and unusual physicality, inventive writing and spoken delivery and choreographic performance structures and dramaturgical logics. Their performance works are layer-cakes of form and reference that speak to the complexity of what it feels like to be alive in this ‘heartbroken little era.’ Their work seeks to expand rather than lock-down meaning and embraces multiplicity and complexity over declarations of certitude.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 17:19:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/blowin-up/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/blowin-up/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Holly Durant</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- https://thesubstation.org.au/show/holly-durant/ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am working through a series of developments which are centred around the exploration of image construction and meaning while observing the body – I am particularly focusing on how we observe, build and warp meaning of the female body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am looking at how we can mask, evolve and devolve the body live through choreography and strategising the placement and viewpoints of the observer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am interested in how we can invert the effects of our natural environments – gravity, momentum, space proximity and textures to rebuild meaning and amplify implied and embedded myths, delving into the deep feminine identity and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be exploring both physical and digital manipulation to extrapolate and represent these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/holly-durant/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/holly-durant/</guid>
        
        
        <category>in-development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thembi Soddell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;THEMBI SODDELL will spend three weeks at The SUBSTATION developing a new multi-channel sound installation as part of her practice-led PhD research, which examines how sound might be used to convey firsthand experiences of mental illness and emotional distress. This development period will involve experiments with how listener’s perceive ambiguous and emotionally charged sound material while listening in complete darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-thembi-soddell&quot;&gt;ABOUT THEMBI SODDELL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THEMBI SODDELL (b.1980) is an Australian sound artist, electroacoustic composer and practice-led researcher with an interest in psychology, perception, extreme emotion and the subjectivity of experience. She works primarily with the sampler, generating sounds from field recordings, instrument textures, played found objects and synthesis to form surreal and ambiguous realisations of place and experience. These volatile, filmic sound worlds often exploit the dynamic extremes, toying with a listener’s sense of expectation and disquiet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She creates work for recording, installation, live performance and concert presentation. Her CV includes the release of four major composition works for CD; guest curation for the National Gallery of Victoria’s Melbourne Now sound program (Melbourne 2014); works exhibited at the Wellington Art Gallery (Wellington 2013), Parisonic Festival (Paris 2011), National Gallery of Australia (Online 2004) and SFMOMA (San Francisco 2002); solo performances at Australian experimental music festivals such as the Totally Huge New Music Festival (Perth 2009), What Is Music? (Melbourne 2004), Liquid Architecture (Auckland 2006, Sydney 2005, Melbourne 2001); and two European tours in duo with ANTHEA CADDY including performances at the Hörkunstfestival (Erlangen 2006), Biegungen Festival (Berlin 2009) and Instants Chavirés (Paris 2006).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SODDELL has a BA in Media Arts (2002) and first-class honours in Sound Art (2005) from RMIT University, where she is now a PhD candidate. Her research focuses on the articulation of firsthand experiences of mental illness and psychological distress in sound art practice, using sound as a means to provoke thought around issues related to health and emotional wellbeing. She also assisted in running Australian experimental music label, cajid media, has an ongoing duo with cellist, ANTHEA CADDY, and has worked as sound designer and dramaturg for choreographer, TIM DARBYSHIRE.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/thembi-soddell/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/thembi-soddell/</guid>
        
        
        <category>in-development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Ghost Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;THE GHOST PROJECT is an installation. And it is a museum. But mostly, it is a discussion. A discussion about imagination, about belief, about cultures. About what you may have experienced and what you may not have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawn from the idea that no matter what science find to be true if alone, at night, in an old dark house with merely a bump any one of us will conjure a ghost and manifest the physiological response it accords; and the knowledge that this is an affliction share by all cultures, original, contemporary, the world over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To date this ongoing project and its particular combination of performance, story exchange, lecture and installation has been developed and presented in The Czech Republic, South Korea, Hong Kong, Indonesia and rural and urban AustralIa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For The SUBSTATION Development TREGLOAN will collaborate with DAVID FRANZKE, PAUL JACKSON, CHAMBER MADE OPERA and local residents to present existing material and new instalments in this ongoing exploration of the culturally ubiquitous notion of haunting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The malleability of truth, the impact of perspective on belief and the potency of imagination. Reality is slippery and the imagination is a fearsome thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-artists&quot;&gt;About the artists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ANNA TREGLOAN&lt;/strong&gt; is a multi-award winning designer, artist and creative producer who collaborates on and creates work for major performing arts companies, major Australian festivals and an array of smaller and independent companies, galleries and artists. She has an extensive history in contemporary theatre and dance, physical theatre, opera, live-art and immersive installations. She has a Masters in Animateuring from VCA, University of Melbourne.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last twelve months she has designed a major exhibition for the Museum of Applied Arts and Sciences, Sydney; Curated and designed the Australian Exhibition for the Prague Quadrennial of Performance, Space and Design; designed the inaugural production for Western Sydney’s newest theatre company; designed staging and costumes for a Korean/ Australian physical theatre collaboration (presented in both countries); worked with Indonesian and Australian puppet companies to devise an immersive installation; and continued to develop and present the multi-part installation project (‘The Ghost Project’) in regional and urban Australia, South East Asia and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAVID FRANZKE.&lt;/strong&gt; Composer and sound designer J. DAVID FRANZKE lives and works in Melbourne. His work spans film, theatre and visual art installations as well as the production of numerous albums, both as solo works and in collaboration with other composers and sound artists. He has worked with many of Australia’s preeminent theatre directors, visual artists and composers; and has collaborated with Cologne-based composer BERND FRIEDMANN since 1996 on various album projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FRANZKE’S credits for sound design and composition include. Ranters Theatre, Song, Intimacy and Holiday. Other theatre credits include: Night on Bald Mountain (2014) Helpmann nomination (sound design) Green Room Award 2012 (Composition &amp;amp; Sound Design) - Pompeii L.A. (Malthouse) for MTC The Beast, Australia Day, The Joy of Text, The Grenade, August: Osage County, Don Juan in Soho, Birthrights, The Recruit; for STC, The Wonderful World of Dissocia (2009) (nominated for best sound design, Sydney Theatre Awards, 2009; for BalletLab, Aviary (2011) (nominated for best sound/composition, Green Room Awards, 2011; Venus and Adonis (nominated for best sound design, Helpmann Awards, 2008); The Odyssey (nominated for best sound design, Helpmann Awards, 2006); Green Room Award 2012 (Composition &amp;amp; Sound Design) ; Pompeii L.A. (Malthouse) The Dictionary of Imaginary Places (Melbourne Festival, 2009); and ANNA TREGLOAN’S Skin Flick, for which he received a 2000 Green Room Award for outstanding contribution to design and technology in theatre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His visual Art credits include sound composition for several installations with major Australian artists such as DANIEL CROOKS, DAVID ROSETZKY and ANDREW HAZELWINKLE. Including Static No. 11 (man running), by CROOKS, winner Basil Sellers Sports/Arts Prize (Ian Potter Museum, 2008); and Cate Blanchett Portrait, with David Rosetzky, 2-channel synchronized digital video installation (National Portrait Gallery Canberra, 2008).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PAUL JACKSON&lt;/strong&gt; is a multi-award winning lighting designer and theatre maker based in Melbourne, Australia, whose practice encompasses theatre, opera, dance, concerts and live events. A graduate of the University of Melbourne, he holds post-graduate qualifications from RMIT. JACKSON has designed lighting for The Australian Ballet, Royal New Zealand Ballet, West Australian Ballet, Victorian Opera, West Australian Opera, Sydney Theatre Company, Melbourne Theatre Company, Bell Shakespeare, Playbox, Malthouse, Belvoir, Ballet Lab, Lucy Guerin, World of Wearable Art New Zealand, Kage, Australian Art Orchestra, La Mama, not yet it’s difficult performance group, Chamber Made Opera and many others. He has collaborated with a diverse range of directors and choreographers including Barrie Kosky, Benedict Andrews, Neil Armfield, Michael Kantor, Marion Potts, Peter Evans, Matt Lutton, Andrew Upton, Sam Strong, Adena Jacobs, Kip Williams, Philip Adams, Jorma Uotinen, Renato Cuoccolo, Simon Stone, Javier de Frutos, Lucy Guerin, Moira Finucane, Julian Meyrick, David Pledger, Gale Edwards, Tom Wright and Philip Seymour Hoffman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A key creative on a number of seminal Australian theatre pieces, his work has featured in festivals and programmes in the United States, Asia, Europe and the United Kingdom. He was the Gilbert Spottiswood Churchill Fellow for 2007 and was an Artistic Associate at Malthouse Theatre from 2007-2013. Paul has received four Green Room Awards, a Sydney Theatre Award and a Helpmann Award, as well as a collecting a large number of other nominations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-ghost-project/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/the-ghost-project/</guid>
        
        
        <category>whats-on</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lady Example</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Women of the world, take over, because if you don’t the world will come to an end and we haven’t got long.” — IVOR CUTLER and LINDA HIRST&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us turn to our Lady Examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LADY EXAMPLE will begin as a literal and detailed examination of the women who surround us - in our lives, in our city, in our history, in our mythology, in our popular culture. We study these women in forensic detail, analysing and inhabiting their carriage, aura, speech and interactions with socialised space, exploring hidden vulnerabilities and hierarchical power structures at play behind their often two-dimensional legacies. In the studio, our source material will evolve into an original performance aesthetic, proposing a multiplicitous, complex way of being ‘lady’; a ‘total woman’ - who will be able to guide us all forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-caroline-meaden-alice-dixon--william-mcbride&quot;&gt;About Caroline Meaden, Alice Dixon &amp;amp; William Mcbride&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALICE DIXON, CAROLINE MEADEN and WILLIAM MCBRIDE work in a non-hierarchical collaboration as performers and devisers of new unusual contemporary dance-theatre. DIXON and MEADEN have worked together in contemporary dance, performance and film for seven years, with MCBRIDE joining the collaboration in 2013. Their most recent work, THIS IS WHAT’S HAPPENING was presented as part of Darebin Arts’ Speakeasy program for the 2015 Melbourne Fringe. The work was critically acclaimed, won the Fringe Award for Best Dance, and has been nominated for an Australian Dance Award for Outstanding Achievement in Independent Dance and a Green Room Award for Best Sound. Each artist has an established independent practice, and have worked with many of Australia’s leading performance and dance practitioners. Their collaborative practice is an enquiry at the intersection of dance and theatre that foregrounds rigorous and unusual physicality, inventive writing and spoken delivery, and choreographic performance structures and dramaturgical logics. Their performance works are layer-cakes of form and reference that speak to the complexity of what it feels like to be alive in the current era.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/lady-example/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/lady-example/</guid>
        
        
        <category>in-development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>XFRMR / Mess — Live</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;australian-exclusive-from-the-substation-cryptic-and-melbourne-festival&quot;&gt;AUSTRALIAN EXCLUSIVE from THE SUBSTATION, CRYPTIC AND MELBOURNE FESTIVAL&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A double bill of light and sound connected by the primal phenomenon of electricity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1891 the genius inventor Nikola Tesla tamed lightning with his Tesla coil, a device that renders electricity visible. Now Glasgow-based artist Robbie Thomson has harnessed the sonic capabilities of the Tesla coil in a work as arresting as the scent of burning ozone and as lively as electricity itself. By synthesising the ever-changing sonic geometries of the apparatus to produce distorted tones and percussive stabs, Thomson offers a glimpse into the subatomic relationships that govern the universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile the Melbourne Electronic Sound Studio (M.E.S.S) will open a wormhole into the history of electronic music, with an astonishing array of synthesisers from the last half century to massage, manipulate and mangle. Conjuring the spectres of sounds lost to time while pointing in new directions music may yet still travel, this concert has been set to stun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-artists&quot;&gt;About the artists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROBBIE THOMSON&lt;/strong&gt; is a Glasgow based artist and theatre maker who works with kinetic sculpture, music, lighting design and technology. XFRMR has developed from THOMSON’s show ECSTATIC ARC which was presented at the Edinburgh Festival at Summerhall in 2013. His work has been shown at venues including the Fort du Bruissin Centre d’art Contemporain, (France), ICA, Festival De Keuze (Netherlands), Barbican, Kings Place, CCA, Shunt, Fusion Festival, Govanhill Baths, Glasgow Sculpture Studios, The Arches, Transmission Gallery and The Woodmill. THOMSON is a member of 85A; a collective that started in 2008 and has produced over 15 large-scale performance, visual art and film works to date. In 2011 he was involved in setting up the Glue Factory, an independent arts venue in Glasgow and since 2013 has been a Cryptic Associate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sonic-a.co.uk&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SONICA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a year-round programme of events dedicated to world-class sonic arts, punctuated by a biennial festival in Glasgow. Produced by CRYPTIC, SONICA presents emerging British talent alongside exceptional international artists in collaboration with renowned co-producers and venues. SONICA was launched in Glasgow in November 2012 at Tramway and has toured to Austria, Brazil, Denmark, France, The Netherlands, Sweden and across the UK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ROBIN FOX (M.E.S.S.)&lt;/strong&gt; is a leading Australian audio-visual artist working across live performance, exhibitions, public art projects and designs for contemporary dance.  His laser works, which synchronize sound and visual electricity in hyper-amplified 3D space, have been performed in well over 50 cities worldwide. The new manifestation of this work RGB LASER SHOW premiered at Mona Foma 2014 (Hobart) and recently featured at Tramway (Glasgow), Vivid Festival (Sydney), the Barbican (London) and St Merri cathedral Paris. His recent collaboration with Atom tm Double Vision took the electronic music festival circuit by storm in 2015 with outings at Mutek (Montreal), Sonar (Barcelona, Santiago, Buenos Aries), Luminato (Toronto) , Outline (Moscow), Ultima (Oslo), Unsound Krakow among others. His score for choreographer STEPHANIE LAKE’S Double Blind recently featured at Sydney Festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BYRON SCULLIN (M.E.S.S.)&lt;/strong&gt; The work of Melbourne practitioner BYRON SCULLIN explores the technological representation and amplification of sound as well as its properties as a physical presence. Operating in an ambiguous space where sound transitions into noise, SCULLIN’S sonic environments offer an experience of mass and multiplicity, often representing attempts to hear the unhearable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his twenty year career he has contributed sound to feature films such as Wolf Creek, contemporary dance productions by LUCY GUERIN, GIDEON OBARZANEK, and LEE SERLE, and theatre works by DAVID CHISOLM, CHAMBER MADE OPERA, and ARENA THEATRE CO. He has created installations for museums and galleries - including Creation Cinema as part of First Peoples at the Melbourne Museum - and produced, engineered and mastered numerous Australian and international recordings. He also works as a sound educator at RMIT and Melbourne University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/xfrmr-mess-live/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/xfrmr-mess-live/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tresor 25 Years</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bunker-music.com/&quot;&gt;BUNKER&lt;/a&gt; brings Berlin techno to Melbourne as they host the Melbourne leg of the official &lt;a href=&quot;http://bunker-music.com/event/bunker-presents-tresor-25-years-june-2016/&quot;&gt;TRESOR 25 YEARS&lt;/a&gt; celebrations with international guests DJ PETE (aka SUBSTANCE) &amp;amp; MARCELUS. Local support from CRAIG MCWHINNEY, PWD and SHEDBUG &amp;amp; RUDOLF C (LIVE).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/tresor-25-years/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/tresor-25-years/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Screen As A Room</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What do you see when stare into a screen? SCREEN AS A ROOM explores performance on screen and screen-based practice in performance. Bringing together artists CAROLINE GARCIA, CHRISTIAN THOMPSON, EUGENIA LIM, FANNI FUTTERKNECHT and MIRA OOSTERWEGHEL, the exhibition will form a dialogue that investigates the liminal space between performance and video, as well as the tension between fiction and reality, space and non-space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing-event-sat-august-06-3pm&quot;&gt;CLOSING EVENT: Sat August 06, 3pm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please join us for a drink to celebrate the closing of SCREEN AS A ROOM. At 3pm there will be a performance as part of MIRA OOSTERWEGHEL’S new work, The conditions were simply perfect to catapult into infinity (2016). A body wobbles, bounces, flies. A body falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complimentary drinks provided by Mountain Goat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-artists&quot;&gt;About the artists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nikkilam.info&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NIKKI LAM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a Melbourne-based visual artist and independent curator. From video and installation, to writing and performative work, her practice engages in the complexity of belonging through the exploration of self, memory and space. Born in Hong Kong, Nikki has a particular interest in the translations of post-colonial identities in the hybrid world. Nikki is the Artistic Director of &lt;a href=&quot;http://channelsfestival.net.au&quot;&gt;CHANNELS FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;, Australia’s only video art biennial showcases contemporary video practices. She is the visual arts editor at &lt;a href=&quot;http://peril.com.au&quot;&gt;PERIL MAGAZINE&lt;/a&gt;, an arts and culture journal with Asian-Australian focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://carolinegarcia.com.au&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CAROLINE GARCIA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a culturally promiscuous performance maker. She works across live performance and video through a hybridised aesthetic of cross-cultural dance, ritual practice, new media, and the sampling of popular culture and colonial imagery. GARCIA’s practice is shaped by alterity, echoing notions of cultural ambiguity and displacement by adopting the role of shape shifter - sliding into the gaps between cultures, experiences of otherness and timeless clichés of exotic femininity. She takes an intersectional approach to contemporary dance (read: twerking), the cultural politics of identity and the diasporic body. She is concerned with forgotten choreographies, mimetic movement, alternate ways of viewing images of the past that eschew classical myths, and the cultural make up of the Filipina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GARCIA has presented at Underbelly Arts Festival, Proximity Festival (WA), Junction Arts Festival (TAS), Channels Festival (VIC), PACT Centre for Emerging Artists, MCA ARTBAR, Art Month Sydney, the Kaldor Parlour Project for 13 Rooms, and Performance Space’s Day For Night with Técha Noble. She has exhibited at the ACMI, CCP, Firstdraft, Sydney Contemporary and UTS ART. Caroline recently participated in La Pocha Nostra’s Live Art Lab in Greece, led by Guillermo Gómez-Peña and was PACT’s Artist-in-Residence for 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although &lt;strong&gt;CHRISTIAN THOMPSON&lt;/strong&gt; often appears in his photographs and videos, they are not self-portraits. Instead he uses his body to present ideas about identity and the collision of cultures. THOMPSON’s training as a sculptor is evident in the careful composition of his images. A self-confessed bower-bird he collects costumes and props to wear in unexpected combinations – sequinned tops are paired with headdresses of native flowers; a silk headscarf with glasses made of crystals. Recently THOMPSON has sought to remove himself from his work. By using props and costumes that conceal more of his face and body he explores ideas of domination and submission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2010, THOMPSON made history becoming one of the first two Aboriginal Australians to be admitted into the University of Oxford to study for his doctorate. He also holds degrees from Amsterdam School of Arts, RMIT Melbourne and the University of Southern Queensland. He is represented in major national and state collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eugenialim.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EUGENIA LIM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an Australian artist who works across video, performance and installation. Interested in how nationalism and stereotypes are formed, LIM invents personas to explore the tensions of an individual within society – the alienation and belonging in a globalised world. Conflations between authenticity, mimicry, natural, man-made, historical and anachronistic are important to the work. LIM’s work has been exhibited internationally at venues including the Tate Modern, GOMA, ACMI, HUN Gallery NY, and FACT Liverpool. Collaboration, artistic community and the intersection between art and society informs her practice: in addition to her solo work, she co-directed the inaugural &lt;a href=&quot;http://channelsfestival.net.au&quot;&gt;CHANNELS FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;, is a board member at &lt;a href=&quot;http://nextwave.org.au/&quot;&gt;NEXT WAVE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;u&gt;,&lt;/u&gt; the founding editor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://assemblepapers.com.au/&quot;&gt;ASSEMBLE PAPERS&lt;/a&gt; and co-founded &lt;a href=&quot;http://tapeprojects.org/&quot;&gt;TAPE PROJECTS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Born in Vienna, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fannifutterknecht.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FANNI FUTTERKNECHT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; has been studying free media, contextual painting and video at the Gerrit Rietveld Academy Amsterdam, Piet Zwart Institute Rotterdam and the Academy of Fine Arts Vienna. She participated at CNDC in Angers in France researching performance, space and the body. FUTTERKNECHT creates performances, installations and works with video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://miraoosterweghel.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MIRA OOSTERWEGHEL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a Melbourne based artist working across performance, installation, video, sculpture and sound. She graduated from Monash University with a Bachelor of Fine Art (Honours) in 2013. Her practice explores the body and its relation to site, structure and systems, with an ongoing interest in discourses of power.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/screen-as-a-room/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://thesubstation.org.au/archive/screen-as-a-room/</guid>
        
        
        <category>archive</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
