<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-19T18:32:55+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/</id><title type="html">The SUBSTATION</title><subtitle>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</subtitle><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><entry><title type="html">Newport Archives</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Newport Archives" /><published>2008-12-31T12:56:00+11:00</published><updated>2008-12-31T12:56:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/">&lt;p&gt;NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport.  Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newport Archives is available by appointment. Email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@thesubstation.org.au&quot;&gt;info@thesubstation.org.au&lt;/a&gt; to book. Each session runs for 40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio Design by JOE TALIA.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commissioned by The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport. Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/newport-archives-2017.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Charlemagne Palestine</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/charlemagne-palestine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Charlemagne Palestine" /><published>2008-06-23T13:14:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-06-23T13:14:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/charlemagne-palestine</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/charlemagne-palestine/">&lt;p&gt;HOLY TRINITY ANGLICAN CHURCH &lt;br /&gt;
2 PASCO STREET, WILLIAMSTOWN&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/music/2010/mar/04/charlemagne-palestine-carillon-bells&quot;&gt;CHARLEMAGNE PALESTINE&lt;/a&gt; is a critically acclaimed artist exploring the transcendent potentials of music. Working across questions of resonance and duration, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bulibjyaQ0s&amp;amp;t=1247s&quot;&gt;PALESTINE&lt;/a&gt;’s works for piano, organ, carillon and voice are defining moments in the 20th and 21st Century, exploring states of trace realised through music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His work with organ specifically has created some of the most harmonically rich and intense explorations for that instrument. PALESTINE will deliver a powerful performance for organ and voice on the historic organ of the Holy Trinity Anglican Church, Williamstown, working with the architecture of the space to explore harmony, overtones and the very resonance of music itself. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION in association with &lt;a href=&quot;http://room40.org/&quot;&gt;ROOM40&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">HOLY TRINITY ANGLICAN CHURCH 2 PASCO STREET, WILLIAMSTOWN</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/charlemagne-palestine.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bunker</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bunker/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bunker" /><published>2008-06-15T12:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-06-15T12:20:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bunker</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bunker/">&lt;p&gt;Expect the very best in techno as &lt;a href=&quot;http://bunker-music.com/&quot;&gt;BUNKER&lt;/a&gt; returns to The SUBSTATION for a third year to celebrate their fifth Birthday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With two international guests to be announced and support by an array of Melbourne’s best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tickets on sale and full line up announced in April.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and BUNKER.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Expect the very best in techno as BUNKER returns to The SUBSTATION for a third year to celebrate their fifth Birthday.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/bunker-2018.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kim Myhr with the AAO</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-norway-with-the-aao/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kim Myhr with the AAO" /><published>2008-06-09T13:08:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-06-09T13:08:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-norway-with-the-aao</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-norway-with-the-aao/">&lt;p&gt;Leading light on the Norwegian experimental scene, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kimmyhr.com/&quot;&gt;KIM MYHR&lt;/a&gt;, performs in the world premiere of a new piece created especially for the shape-shifting 10-piece, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aao.com.au/&quot;&gt;AUSTRALIAN ART ORCHESTRA&lt;/a&gt;. Tailored to the group’s ability to traverse acoustic and electronic textures, MYHR weaves a complex interplay of rhythmic pulses, visceral texture and near psychedelic harmonic density.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KIM MYHR has an established reputation as one of the industries leading contemporary innovators, creating arresting compositions for chamber ensembles, electroacoustic settings and various theatrical projects. These include, most recently, MURAL, with INGAR ZACH and Australian saxophone icon JIM DENLEY, and CIRCADIA with DAVID STACKENÄS, JOE WILLIAMSON, and THE NECKS’ drummer TONY BUCK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://melbournejazz.com/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE INTERNATIONAL JAZZ FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Australian Art Orchestra is assisted by the Australian Government through the Australia Council, its arts funding and advisory body.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Leading light on the Norwegian experimental scene, KIM MYHR, performs in the world premiere of a new piece created especially for the shape-shifting 10-piece, the AUSTRALIAN ART ORCHESTRA. Tailored to the group’s ability to traverse acoustic and electronic textures, MYHR weaves a complex interplay of rhythmic pulses, visceral texture and near psychedelic harmonic density.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/kim-myhr-8.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">KIM MYHR - SOLO WITH PETER KNIGHT</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-solo-norway/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KIM MYHR - SOLO WITH PETER KNIGHT" /><published>2008-06-08T12:57:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-06-08T12:57:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-solo-norway</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/kim-myhr-solo-norway/">&lt;p&gt;One of the world’s most distinctive guitarists, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kimmyhr.com/&quot;&gt;KIM MYHR&lt;/a&gt;’s sound has been described as somewhere between American folk strumming and 60s avant-garde orchestral soundmass. For the first time in Australia, KIM MYHR performs redefining solo works for the 12 string guitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MYHR has performed solo at some of the most significant festivals and venues in Europe, establishing his reputation as one of the instrument’s leading contemporary innovators. The WIRE called MYHR’s first release, ALL YOUR LIMBS SINGING (SOFA) as “a delirious love letter to the 12-string guitar.” And in 2016, MYHR released a collaborative album with JENNY HVAL and TRONDHEIM JAZZ ORCHESTRA, “IN THE END HIS VOICE WILL BE THE SOUND OF PAPER” which was described as “…a grotesquely beautiful paradox of sound, pleasing to the last.” – Slug Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MYHR will be joined by trail-blazing trumpeter and sound artist, PETER KNIGHT with a performance of ALLOTROPE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ALLOTROPE, that is, the varying atomic states of a physical form (Carbon; Graphite, Diamond) is KNIGHT’s solo piece created using trumpet, laptop electronics, amplifier and pedals. ALLOTROPE explores KNIGHT’s multidisciplinary preoccupation with space, understatement and long form structure, which draws inspiration from a diverse range of sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://peterknightmusic.com/&quot;&gt;PETER KNIGHT&lt;/a&gt;, who has been described as, “Hard to categorise… hauntingly memorable” (The Wire, UK) has toured as a solo artist to major festivals and venues around the world,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If trumpet is an element, then Knight is an alchemist” – New York City Jazz Record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://melbournejazz.com/&quot;&gt;MELBOURNE INTERNATIONAL JAZZ FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">One of the world’s most distinctive guitarists, KIM MYHR’s sound has been described as somewhere between American folk strumming and 60s avant-garde orchestral soundmass. For the first time in Australia, KIM MYHR performs redefining solo works for the 12 string guitar.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/kim-myhr-9.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Apokalypsis</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/apokalypsis/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apokalypsis" /><published>2008-05-16T11:38:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-05-16T11:38:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/apokalypsis</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/apokalypsis/">&lt;p&gt;Four performers. One hundred apocalypses. Sixty minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beginning with the Big Bang and hurtling through wars, famines, kingdoms collapsing, extinctions and dictatorships, APOKALYPSIS establishes a narrative of the world as one of repeated annihilation and overcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As history speeds towards the present day and energy and resources diminish, what emerges is a hallucinogenic vision of a world on the brink of total collapse. This is contemporary Western society: people with the tools, intelligence and power to change the course of the planet, but who can’t find the will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jump cutting between genres and underpinned by a gradually evolving live score, APOKALYPSIS is a high octane, searing indictment of denialism and our inability to work together in this extraordinary moment in time: the eve of the Anthropocene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Devisors and Performers: Kai Bradley, Rosie Clynes, Zak Pidd and Charles Purcell
Set and Costume Design: Jonathan Hindmarsh
Lighting Design: Katie Sfetkidis
Sound Design: Zak Pidd
Dramaturgy: Katy Maudlin
Mentor: Bruce Gladwin
Associate Producer: Bron Belcher&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;http://nextwave.org.au/&quot;&gt;NEXT WAVE&lt;/a&gt; as part of the KICKSTART HELIX PROGRAM.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Four performers. One hundred apocalypses. Sixty minutes.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/apokalypsis.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lady Example</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/lady-example/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lady Example" /><published>2008-05-09T11:51:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-05-09T11:51:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/lady-example</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/lady-example/">&lt;p&gt;Women of the World take over, because if you don’t the world will come to an end, and we haven’t got long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the makers of THIS IS WHAT’S HAPPENING, BLOWIN’ UP and FALLEN O’ER — LADY EXAMPLE, is a deranged and exquisite stocktake of history to propose a feminine future. Let us turn to our lady examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created and performed by ALICE DIXON, CAROLINE MEADEN and WILLIAM MCBRIDE with an ensemble of artists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound by EMAH FOX. &lt;br /&gt;
Lighting by JASON CRICK. &lt;br /&gt; 
Design by MATILDA WOODROOFE. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by THE SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;http://nextwave.org.au/&quot;&gt;NEXT WAVE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Women of the World take over, because if you don’t the world will come to an end, and we haven’t got long.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/lady-example-2018.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tracing Trancendence</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tracing-trancendence/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tracing Trancendence" /><published>2008-05-04T12:49:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-05-04T12:49:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tracing-trancendence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tracing-trancendence/">&lt;p&gt;A meditation on the distance between deserts and the worn tracks on the road to prayer — TRACING TRANSCENDENCE treads a path towards encountering the spiritual and sacred, ritual and remote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shireentaweel.com/&quot;&gt;SHIREEN TAWEEL&lt;/a&gt; is an artist based at the Parramatta Artist Studios. Her creative practice continues a long tradition that involves the act of marking and piercing copper. This process stretches throughout history and across cultures, but is intimately connected to TAWEEL’s contemporary experience of being a migrant of Muslim and Lebanese heritage living in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gestures that TAWEEL marks into copper are suggestive of an art form steeped in tradition, but are explored through new perspectives, placing emphasis on the global experience of migration, movement and multiculturalism. The resulting works contribute to a cross-cultural discourse of shared histories and experiences between diverse communities and cultural groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;http://nextwave.org.au/&quot;&gt;NEXT WAVE&lt;/a&gt; as part of the KICKSTART HELIX PROGRAM.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">A meditation on the distance between deserts and the worn tracks on the road to prayer — TRACING TRANSCENDENCE treads a path towards encountering the spiritual and sacred, ritual and remote.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/shireen.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">You’re Standing in it</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/youre-standing-in-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="You're Standing in it" /><published>2008-05-01T14:33:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-05-01T14:33:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/youre-standing-in-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/youre-standing-in-it/">&lt;p&gt;Resident Artist AMANDA CARR explores the relationship between the observer and environment through an unlikely symbiosis of theatrical staging and liquid mechanics on The SUBSTATION billboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the work, YOU’RE STANDING IN IT, &lt;a href=&quot;http://amandacarrcreative.com/&quot;&gt;AMANDA CARR&lt;/a&gt; forces fluids into a microscopic void between parallel planes to observe the instability produced by differing surface tensions. This phenomenon, known as Hele-Shaw flow, produces a visual landscape that is as foreign as it is familiar, imaginary in appearance yet undeniably natural.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CARR’s artistic practice transfers the image onto fabric to craft wearable designs, distorting scale and distinction between background and foreground. The human illusion of autonomy enveloped in a volatile terrain forged through a collision of opposing forces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where does the body end and the environment begin? Do we create each other? Or destroy one another?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Resident Artist AMANDA CARR explores the relationship between the observer and environment through an unlikely symbiosis of theatrical staging and liquid mechanics on The SUBSTATION billboards.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/amanda.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ONO</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/ono/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ONO" /><published>2008-04-20T13:15:00+10:00</published><updated>2008-04-20T13:15:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/ono</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/ono/">&lt;p&gt;Visceral and intimate, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.o-n-o.com.au/&quot;&gt;ONO&lt;/a&gt; journeys toward a collective understanding of rhythm and sound in the belly of the SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Room, artists and audience—all form part of the storyline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As narratives unfold, the response is both sonic and social. Part music performance, part installation—ONO presents an evening of international and local guests exploring the undercurrents of music today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and ONO.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Visceral and intimate, ONO journeys toward a collective understanding of rhythm and sound in the belly of the SUBSTATION.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/ono-2018.jpg" /></entry></feed>