<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-11-28T17:54:02+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/</id><title type="html">The SUBSTATION</title><subtitle>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</subtitle><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><entry><title type="html">GENESIS BREYER P-ORRIDGE with EDLEY ODOWD</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/genesis-breyer-p-orridge/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="GENESIS BREYER P-ORRIDGE with EDLEY ODOWD" /><published>2008-02-02T20:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2008-02-02T20:00:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/genesis-breyer-p-orridge</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/genesis-breyer-p-orridge/">&lt;p&gt;Legendary English singer-songwriter, musician, poet, performance, and visual artist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/Genesis-BREYER-P-ORRIDGE-171735929627691/&quot;&gt;GENESIS BREYER P-ORRIDGE&lt;/a&gt; performs live on stage with EDLEY ODOWD, who together tour as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/psychictvptv3/&quot;&gt;PSYCHIC TV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P-ORRIDGE rose to notability as founder of the COUM Transmissions art collective, which operated in Britain from 1969 to 1976. P-Orridge fronted the pioneering industrial band &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.throbbing-gristle.com/&quot;&gt;THROBBING GRISTLE&lt;/a&gt; between 1975 and 1981 and the experimental multimedia commonage PSYCHIC TV from 1981 to present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New York based artist and percussionist EDLEY ODOWD has been collaborating with cultural luminary GENESIS BREYER P-ORRIDGE for the last 15 years as PSYCHIC TV, which GENESIS calls h/er ”favourite line-up ever”. ODOWD also produces and manages the band in addition to creating its graphic design visuals since the bands reactivation in 2003.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION in association with &lt;a href=&quot;http://room40.org/&quot;&gt;ROOM 40&lt;/a&gt; as part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://midsumma.org.au/&quot;&gt;MIDSUMMA FESTIVAL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Legendary English singer-songwriter, musician, poet, performance, and visual artist GENESIS BREYER P-ORRIDGE performs live on stage with EDLEY ODOWD, who together tour as PSYCHIC TV.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/genesis.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Moor Mother and Rasheedah Phillips</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/moor-mother-and-rasheedah-phillips/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Moor Mother and Rasheedah Phillips" /><published>2008-01-25T19:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2008-01-25T19:00:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/moor-mother-and-rasheedah-phillips</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/moor-mother-and-rasheedah-phillips/">&lt;p&gt;The radical Philadelphia-based collaboration BLACK QUANTUM FUTURISM, consisting of musician and poet, CAMAE AYEWA aka &lt;a href=&quot;https://moormothergoddess.bandcamp.com/&quot;&gt;MOOR MOTHER&lt;/a&gt; and writer and activist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.afrofuturistaffair.com/creative-rasheedah-phillips&quot;&gt;RASHEEDAH PHILLIPS&lt;/a&gt; perform for the first time in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.blackquantumfuturism.com/&quot;&gt;BLACK QUANTUM FUTURISM&lt;/a&gt;, AYEWA and PHILLIPS speak to the violence, trauma and radical political struggles of black history and mobilise the revolutionary potential of Afrofuturist thought to manipulate and reorient perceptions of the past and present in ways that make alternative futures imaginable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MOOR MOTHER sound is abrasive; a torrent of noise, free jazz, hip-hop, poetry and punk (or, in her own words, ‘project-housing bop, slaveship punk, witch rap’). The album Fetish Bones, released in 2016, is already considered a contemporary masterpiece. Pitchfork described it as ‘a reminder of the hardships of love under the regime of historical trauma’, an album ‘you will never be able to unhear’, and The Wire was moved to describe MOOR MOTHER as ‘the most radical Afrofuturist artist to emerge for years’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RASHEEDAH PHILLIPS is a community housing activist, a mother, writer, the creator of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.afrofuturistaffair.com/&quot;&gt;THE AFROFUTURIST AFFAIR&lt;/a&gt; and a founding member of &lt;a href=&quot;http://metropolarity.net/&quot;&gt;METROPOLARITY QUEER SCI-FI COLLECTIVE&lt;/a&gt;. In 2014, she published her first speculative fiction collection, Recurrence Plot (and Other Time Travel Tales), followed by an anthology of experimental essays from Black visionary writers called Black Quantum Futurism: Theory &amp;amp; Practice Vol. I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.liquidarchitecture.org.au/&quot;&gt;LIQUID ARCHITECTURE&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/stillnomads/&quot;&gt;STILL NOMADS&lt;/a&gt; in association with MONA FOMA.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">The radical Philadelphia-based collaboration BLACK QUANTUM FUTURISM, consisting of musician and poet, CAMAE AYEWA aka MOOR MOTHER and writer and activist RASHEEDAH PHILLIPS perform for the first time in Australia.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/moormother.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Newport Archives</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Newport Archives" /><published>2007-12-31T12:56:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-12-31T12:56:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/newport-archives/">&lt;p&gt;NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport.  Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newport Archives is available by appointment. Email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@thesubstation.org.au&quot;&gt;info@thesubstation.org.au&lt;/a&gt; to book. Each session runs for 40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio Design by JOE TALIA.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commissioned by The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">NEWPORT ARCHIVES is an audio tour commissioned by The SUBSTATION in 2016, which explores The SUBSTATION’s own building and surrounding landmarks in Newport. Drawing on interviews with local residents, NEWPORT ARCHIVES explores the origins of Newport and its surrounds. Equipped with headphones and an mp3 player as their guide, participants walk unaccompanied through Newport’s streets in a journey that uncannily knits the present with past memories.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/newport-archives-2017.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rabble</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/the-rabble/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rabble" /><published>2007-12-01T10:47:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-12-01T10:47:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/the-rabble</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/the-rabble/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://therabble.com.au/&quot;&gt;THE RABBLE&lt;/a&gt; is developing ULYSSES; an epic, ten-hour contemporary performance inspired by James Joyce’s novel of the same name. THE RABBLE takes our cues from Joyce’s seminal modernist text creating an epic investigation of femininity, death and performance. THE RABBLE’s ULYSSES includes: a woman breast feeding, 309 Questions &amp;amp; 308 Answers, a desperately problematic feminist reading of the narrative events of Ulysses, a meal, a poor theatre version of Hamlet, a slapstick endurance event, a porno, a collective barn dance and a woman saying yes. THE RABBLE are one of our &lt;a href=&quot;http://thesubstation.org.au/show/the-rabble/&quot;&gt;ARTISTS IN RESIDENCE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">THE RABBLE is developing ULYSSES; an epic, ten-hour contemporary performance inspired by James Joyce’s novel of the same name. THE RABBLE takes our cues from Joyce’s seminal modernist text creating an epic investigation of femininity, death and performance. THE RABBLE’s ULYSSES includes: a woman breast feeding, 309 Questions &amp;amp; 308 Answers, a desperately problematic feminist reading of the narrative events of Ulysses, a meal, a poor theatre version of Hamlet, a slapstick endurance event, a porno, a collective barn dance and a woman saying yes. THE RABBLE are one of our ARTISTS IN RESIDENCE.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/ulyssis.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Claire Edwardes and Richard Cilli</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/claire-edwardes-and-richard-cilli/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Claire Edwardes and Richard Cilli" /><published>2007-12-01T10:46:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-12-01T10:46:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/claire-edwardes-and-richard-cilli</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/claire-edwardes-and-richard-cilli/">&lt;p&gt;Described as the ‘sorceress of percussion’, celebrated Sydney-based percussionist &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.claireedwardes.com/&quot;&gt;CLAIRE EDWARDES&lt;/a&gt; unites with Helpmann award-winning dancer and choreographer RICHARD CILLI in a new physically virtuosic work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directed by acclaimed choreographer GIDEON OBARZANEK, two very different artists collide as they are pitted against one another, taking an abrasive look at the things that divide and unite us. Touching on themes including gender, sexuality, psychology and age, EDWARDES and CILLI will take aim at our desire to connect despite our differences.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Described as the ‘sorceress of percussion’, celebrated Sydney-based percussionist CLAIRE EDWARDES unites with Helpmann award-winning dancer and choreographer RICHARD CILLI in a new physically virtuosic work.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/richard.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We Are People – An Exhibition of The Democratic Set</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/we-are-people-an-exhibition-of-the-democratic-set/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Are People – An Exhibition of The Democratic Set" /><published>2007-11-10T10:11:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-11-10T10:11:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/we-are-people-an-exhibition-of-the-democratic-set</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/we-are-people-an-exhibition-of-the-democratic-set/">&lt;p&gt;Over eight years, &lt;a href=&quot;http://backtobacktheatre.com/&quot;&gt;BACK TO BACK THEATRE&lt;/a&gt; has worked with 28 communities to create a series of short films that explore the ideals of equality and freedom. This exhibition captures 12 of these films, each a portrait of a community, exposing their differences and the similarities that connect us all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disturbingly obvious and tantalisingly strange, &lt;a href=&quot;http://backtobacktheatre.com/projects/democratic-set/&quot;&gt;THE DEMOCRATIC SET&lt;/a&gt; uses a custom-made film set and a neutral room with two opposing doors. Authoring a unique living snapshot of a community at a particular moment in time, THE DEMOCRATIC SET invites each participant to untangle what an uncensored space means to them, with each viewer surprised and seduced by the mysterious, funny, poignant and provocative sets as they pan the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the films on display in The SUBSTATION galleries, six images from THE DEMOCRATIC SET are also displayed on The SUBSTATION billboards, with thanks to JEFF BUSBY, who has worked with Back to Back Theatre to develop their photographic archive across time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and BACK TO BACK THEATRE.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Over eight years, BACK TO BACK THEATRE has worked with 28 communities to create a series of short films that explore the ideals of equality and freedom. This exhibition captures 12 of these films, each a portrait of a community, exposing their differences and the similarities that connect us all.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/democratic-set.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Gravity System Response</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/gravity-system-response/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gravity System Response" /><published>2007-11-04T06:20:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-11-04T06:20:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/gravity-system-response</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/gravity-system-response/">&lt;p&gt;Exploring the energy of paint, air, water and gravity combined, GRAVITY SYSTEM RESPONSE is a
series of six canvas panels by renowned Melbourne-based artist, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/ashkeatingartist/&quot;&gt;ASH KEATING&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Installed on The SUBSTATION billboards, the work is a broad study of colour and its emotive properties,
with swathes of yellows, reds, pinks, magenta and white fields folding in on one another. Cascading down the surface, each intricate variation across the interconnected panels marks the passing of time spent
spraying, washing and waiting, exposing KEATING’s borderline obsessive commitment to the repetitious
and ritualistic layering of paint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and ASH KEATING.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Exploring the energy of paint, air, water and gravity combined, GRAVITY SYSTEM RESPONSE is a series of six canvas panels by renowned Melbourne-based artist, ASH KEATING.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/ash-keating.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Tetsuya Umeda</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/tetsuya-umeda/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tetsuya Umeda" /><published>2007-10-30T10:10:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-10-30T10:10:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/tetsuya-umeda</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/tetsuya-umeda/">&lt;p&gt;Based in Osaka, Japan, &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/106567276&quot;&gt;TETSUYA UMEDA&lt;/a&gt; creates dynamic environments through the combination of architectural structures, sound and light. His site-specific and temporal works utilise found domestic objects and transform them from their daily familiarity into a transcendent spectacle of the unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UMEDA’s richly dynamic and embodied installations that are often situated outside of the gallery context, encourage audience members to explore the interaction of its constituent parts, and by doing so, discover their own individuated perceptions, as a part of and in relation to his work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and LIQUID ARCHITECTURE in association with PERFORMANCE SPACE and ROOM40.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Based in Osaka, Japan, TETSUYA UMEDA creates dynamic environments through the combination of architectural structures, sound and light. His site-specific and temporal works utilise found domestic objects and transform them from their daily familiarity into a transcendent spectacle of the unexpected.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/tetsuya.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Future Tense</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/future-tense/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Future Tense" /><published>2007-10-28T07:55:00+11:00</published><updated>2007-10-28T07:55:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/future-tense</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/future-tense/">&lt;p&gt;FUTURE TENSE is a group exhibition that explores positions in video art, that draft alternative visions for the future to establish histories which reflect on the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combining video art, installation and new technology, the exhibition connects speculative narratives as a means to explore contemporary politics, histories and national identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhibiting artists include ANTOINETTE  J. CITIZEN, HANNAH BRONTË, YAEL BARTANA (ISR), RACHEL MASON (US) with more to be announced. Curated by ALICIA RENEW and KATE WARREN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and &lt;a href=&quot;http://channelsfestival.net.au/&quot;&gt;CHANNELS&lt;/a&gt; as part of CHANNELS: THE AUSTRALIAN VIDEO ART FESTIVAL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the full list of CHANNELS FESTIVAL events at The SUBSTATION &lt;a href=&quot;https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/channels/&quot;&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">FUTURE TENSE is a group exhibition that explores positions in video art, that draft alternative visions for the future to establish histories which reflect on the present.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/future-tense.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Plastic Loaves Makes You… Spring</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/plastic-loaves-makes-you-spring/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Plastic Loaves Makes You... Spring" /><published>2007-10-20T06:06:00+10:00</published><updated>2007-10-20T06:06:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/plastic-loaves-makes-you-spring</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/plastic-loaves-makes-you-spring/">&lt;p&gt;Spring time has slinked on in and activity is rousingly warmer. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plasticloaves.com/&quot;&gt;PLASTIC LOAVES&lt;/a&gt;’ windows thrust open to invite you inside The SUBSTATION for an evening to flourish together. With each space landscaped and pruned by a certified living artist, the sweet air will excrete all night with a long stem of budding performers, vocals, sounds, visuals and alluring beverages, emerging from every gap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With ANDRÁS, LUCY CLICHE (LIVE), MATTHEW BROWN (LIVE), NITE FLEIT, MAGIC STEVEN (LIVE), GIAN MANIK, RUBY JEPPE, BEANIES (TOKYO), DIDVID.S, PRACTISESTUDIOPRACTISE, MIETTA CONVENTRY, CHARLIE FREEDMAN, BRAD &amp;amp; CHAD, BILLIE MORRIS, HYUN LEE, VICTOR BRAVO and WATERFALL PERSON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and PLASTIC LOAVES.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>patternworks_</name></author><summary type="html">Spring time has slinked on in and activity is rousingly warmer. PLASTIC LOAVES’ windows thrust open to invite you inside The SUBSTATION for an evening to flourish together. With each space landscaped and pruned by a certified living artist, the sweet air will excrete all night with a long stem of budding performers, vocals, sounds, visuals and alluring beverages, emerging from every gap.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/plastic-loaves.jpg" /></entry></feed>