<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-23T14:54:25+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The SUBSTATION</title><subtitle>The SUBSTATION is a unique large-scale multi-purpose gallery, performance space and dance studio for artists of every kind, in Newport, Melbourne, Australia.</subtitle><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><entry><title type="html">Tidal: Creating a vision for a New Future</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tidal-creating-a-vision-for-a-new-future/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tidal: Creating a vision for a New Future" /><published>2019-05-09T14:44:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-05-09T14:44:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tidal-creating-a-vision-for-a-new-future</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/tidal-creating-a-vision-for-a-new-future/">&lt;p&gt;A World Environment Day symposium exploring themes of climate change and the intersection between art and science. Join us for a multi-layered conversation that unpacks the issues and challenges of our shifting environments as we seek innovative solutions for our future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;symposium-presenters&quot;&gt;Symposium Presenters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JENNY MARTIN / Chair: senior lecturer in Science Communication at University of Melbourne&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YANDELL WALTON: Melbourne-based artist whose work encompasses projection, installation and interactive digital media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WAIN FIMERI: award-winning local filmmaker and creator of recent documentary Tidal, which investigates the local impacts of climate change&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BLANCHE VERLIE: an Associate Lecturer at RMIT University with over eight years’ experience engaging communities and students with climate change. Her research explores how scientific approaches to climate communication can make climate change feel distant and abstract, rather than personal and relevant, and her practice pays particular attention to people’s emotional experiences of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by Hobsons Bay City Council in partnership with The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">A World Environment Day symposium exploring themes of climate change and the intersection between art and science. Join us for a multi-layered conversation that unpacks the issues and challenges of our shifting environments as we seek innovative solutions for our future.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Tidal.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Loscil (CA), Rafael Anton Irisarri (USA), Joe Talia &amp;amp; Eiko Ishibashi (JPN) and Lost Few</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/loscil-rafael/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Loscil (CA), Rafael Anton Irisarri (USA), Joe Talia &amp; Eiko Ishibashi (JPN) and Lost Few" /><published>2019-04-23T12:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2019-04-23T12:00:00+10:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/loscil-rafael</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/loscil-rafael/">&lt;p&gt;The SUBSTATION and Room40 present a night of beautiful electronic exploration through an impressive cast of ambient masters – Loscil (CA), Rafael Anton Irisarri (USA), Joe Talia and Eiko Ishibashi (JPN) and Lost Few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loscil aka Scott Morgan from Vancouver derived his name from the “looping oscillator” function of Csound audio programming language. Yet since 2001 Loscil has been making more than just loops – bringing slow ambient textures exploring subjects like water and morning plain – leaving you wrapped in a sonic blanket of euphoria and aural bliss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining Loscil is one of New Yorks most celebrated ambient music makers, Rafael Anton Irisarri, a multi-instrumentalist, record producer, mastering engineer and curator. Irisarri’s music often has a mournful, elegiac quality, his compositions are deeply emotive and epic, like a symphony recording that’s been rescued from attic entombment after half a century. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tokyo-based electro-acoustic duo Eiko Ishibashi &amp;amp; Joe Talia, performing with flute, piano, analog tape, synthesizers and percussion. Together their work creates a dense harmonic sound world that exists somewhere between avant-garde improvisation and electronic exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining this spectacular line up is Lost Few, an audio-visual project by Melbourne-based experimental artist David Thomson. Lost Few will be debuting Between the Silence – a two person performance installation with visuals by Keith Deverell – showcasing ambient techno, disturbed electronics, processed instrumentation and sub-bass experiments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is general standing and relaxed seating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION and Room40.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">The SUBSTATION and Room40 present a night of beautiful electronic exploration through an impressive cast of ambient masters – Loscil (CA), Rafael Anton Irisarri (USA), Joe Talia and Eiko Ishibashi (JPN) and Lost Few.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/loscil.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Violin Generator</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/the-violin-generator/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Violin Generator" /><published>2019-04-01T13:30:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-04-01T13:30:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/the-violin-generator</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/the-violin-generator/">&lt;p&gt;This Dada-esque cabinet of curiosities includes over 700 violin artefacts, iconography, and improbable instruments; performances that are musically perverse, historically twisted, and culturally critical. Sourced from Australia’s most unusual collection, The Rosenberg Museum is the brainchild of violinist, composer, and artist Jon Rose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience these improbable instruments in action with performances on the 5th, 6th, 12th &amp;amp; 13th April with musicians Ernie Althoff, Robbie Avenaim, Biddy Connor, Jozef Cseres, Judith Hamann, Rainer Linz, Michael McNab, Maria Moles, Chloe Smith, Rachael Kim, Erkki Veltheim,Lizzy Welsh and Brigid Burke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Violin Generator is a free exhibition and performances are $10.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Introduction&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Jozef Cseres, Director of the Rosenberg Museum.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7:15 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Gallery 6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Rainer Linz, Alternative Violin Pedagogy.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7:30 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Gallery 5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Ernie Althoff, The Leichhardt Violin - 2 String Drone Instrument with DC Motors - Cigar Box Monochord Played by 16 RPM Turntable MK 2.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7:45 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Gallery 4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Robbie Avenaim, SARPS String Quartet.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Gallery 3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Robbie Avenaim &amp;amp; Ernie Althoff, I Can Shake a Chicken in the Middle of the Room &lt;br /&gt; Maria Moles &amp;amp; Ernie Althoff, The Musical Coffin - Single-String Corrugated Violano.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8:15 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Gallery 2 Mezzanine&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Organ on Timer&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8:30 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Dance Studio Level 2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Brigid Burke &amp;amp; Maria Moles, The Angst of the String at Tilde.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;8:45 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Intermission&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9:00 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Main Space Level 1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Erkki Veltheim, Rachael Kim, Lizzy Welsh, Judith Hamann, Biddy Connor, Chloë Smith, Maria Moles, Robbie Avenaim, Michael McNab, Music in a Time of Dysfunction.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9:30 PM&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Performances End, Gallery Open.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION, in conjunction with Tura New Music. Supported by Australia Council.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><category term="archive" /><summary type="html">This Dada-esque cabinet of curiosities includes over 700 violin artefacts, iconography, and improbable instruments; performances that are musically perverse, historically twisted, and culturally critical. Sourced from Australia’s most unusual collection, The Rosenberg Museum is the brainchild of violinist, composer, and artist Jon Rose.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/JonRose.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Marginal Consort</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/marginal-consort/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Marginal Consort" /><published>2019-03-27T13:14:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-03-27T13:14:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/marginal-consort</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/marginal-consort/">&lt;p&gt;Legendary Japanese collective, MARGINAL CONSORT will perform a rare three-hour concert for one night only in a Melbourne exclusive. Founded by members of East Bionic Symphonia – Kazuo Imai, Kei Shii, Masami Tada, and Tomonao Koshikawa will create deeply spatial works that sit at the nexus of performance, site specific installation and durational concert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 1996, MARGINAL CONSORT reconnect only once a year to perform – without discussion the collective gather as independent solos – using start and end times as the only fixed elements in their longform happenings. What happens in-between is for the moment; ephemeral and utterly unique to the location and time of that performance. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION, &lt;a href=&quot;http://room40.org/&quot;&gt;Room40&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.melbournejazz.com/program/2019/marginal-consort/&quot;&gt;Melbourne International Jazz Festival.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Legendary Japanese collective, MARGINAL CONSORT will perform a rare three-hour concert for one night only in a Melbourne exclusive. Founded by members of East Bionic Symphonia – Kazuo Imai, Kei Shii, Masami Tada, and Tomonao Koshikawa will create deeply spatial works that sit at the nexus of performance, site specific installation and durational concert.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Marginal%20Consort.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Recital</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/recital/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Recital" /><published>2019-03-20T14:49:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-03-20T14:49:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/recital</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/recital/">&lt;p&gt;Dancer. Percussionist. Rivals. A strange and mesmeric double act.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three-time APRA Art Music Award-winning percussionist Claire Edwardes and Helpmann Award-winning dancer Richard Cilli unite their distinct virtuosic talents in an unusual presentation of how movement sounds, and how sound moves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From formal beginnings into virtuosic performance and competitive play, Edwardes and Cilli collaborate with acclaimed director and choreographer Gideon Obarzanek and Australia’s leading electro-pop composer Paul Mac to create an intriguing display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Set in the orthodox world of a music and dance recital, the ambiguous relationship between the two performers intensifies. The outcomes are impressive, disturbing and wildly ecstatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Director: Gideon Obarzanek &lt;br /&gt;
Performers: Richard Cilli, Claire Edwardes &lt;br /&gt;
Lighting Design: Bosco Shaw &lt;br /&gt;
Composition &amp;amp; Sound Design: Paul Mac, Claire Edwardes &lt;br /&gt;
Producer: Erin Milne (Bureau Of Works) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by The SUBSTATION as part of Dance Massive 2019.
Recital has been assisted by the Australian Government through the Australia Council, its arts funding and advisory body.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Dancer. Percussionist. Rivals. A strange and mesmeric double act.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Recital-2019.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">MICOLOGÍA</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/micologia/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MICOLOGÍA" /><published>2019-03-06T11:10:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-03-06T11:10:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/micologia</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/micologia/">&lt;p&gt;Naarm (Melbourne) based sustainable fashion label REMUSE launches its biannual Equinox clothing collection and second mycology inspired release, ‘Micología II’ in a multisensory and immersive runway experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conceptualised as a prequel to last year’s event, ‘Equinox V Venus’, which took place at the theoretical end of humankind’s tenure of planet earth, with this collection REMUSE winds the clock back one billion years to before modern time.
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The runway production MICOLOGÍA elaborates on the cosmic origins of the kingdom of funghi, exploring themes of synchronicity with nature, symbiosis and biomimicry and sustainability through theatrical dialogue and visual display. REMUSE is committed to sustainable and ethical production practices sourcing where possible organic materials.
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a singularly imaginative fashion runway performance timed once again to take place on the new moon preceding the Autumnal equinox. Presented as part of the Virgin Australia Melbourne Fashion Festival Arts Program. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Naarm (Melbourne) based sustainable fashion label REMUSE launches its biannual Equinox clothing collection and second mycology inspired release, ‘Micología II’ in a multisensory and immersive runway experience.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/VAMFF.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Madeleine Flynn and Tim Humphrey</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/madeleine-flynn-and-tim-humphrey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Madeleine Flynn and Tim Humphrey" /><published>2019-02-13T11:50:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-02-13T11:50:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/madeleine-flynn-and-tim-humphrey</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/in-development/madeleine-flynn-and-tim-humphrey/">&lt;p&gt;Madeleine Flynn and Tim Humphrey will undertake a residency at Cove Park Scotland supported by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cryptic.org.uk/cove-parkresidency- programme/&quot;&gt;Cryptic Glasgow&lt;/a&gt; and The SUBSTATION.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this residency, they will work on a new sound-visual interactive setup and performance model, working title All The Feedback We Ever Had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Madeleine Flynn and Tim Humphrey are Australian artists who create unexpected situations for listening. Their work is driven by a curiosity and questioning about sound in human culture and seeks to evolve and engage with new processes and audiences, through public and participative interventions. In 2017 their practice was awarded the national Australia Council Award for Emerging and Experimental Artforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their work has been presented and commissioned widely internationally including Theater Der Welt, Germany: Brighton Festival UK: Sonica Festival Glasgow: Asian Arts Theater, Gwangju: Incheon Art Platform, Seoul: Sydney Festival Australia: Melbourne Festival Australia: AsiaTopa, Melbourne: Perth Festival Australia: MONA FOMA Australia: Kennedy Center, Washington USA amongst many others. Their current areas of interest are existential risk, artificial intelligence in public space, and long form socially engaged public art interventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their practice is documented at http://madeleineandtim.net/&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Madeleine Flynn and Tim Humphrey will undertake a residency at Cove Park Scotland supported by Cryptic Glasgow and The SUBSTATION.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Maddie-and-Tim.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bunker</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bunker/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bunker" /><published>2019-02-07T13:30:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-02-07T13:30:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bunker</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/bunker/">&lt;p&gt;Melbourne’s leading techno promoter, touring and events company Bunker returns to The SUBSTATION to celebrate its sixth birthday with a warehouse-style event featuring world-class techno acts from Europe alongside local talent. Experience a night of blistering and hypnotic music and accompanying visual installations in The SUBSTATION’S atmospheric, majestic industrial setting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound: Funktion-One provided by Full Throttle Entertainment
Visuals: TBA
Lighting: TBA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SNTS (Live) [Horizontal Ground / Sacred Court, DE]
Hydrangea [Semantica / Silent Season, FR)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Local support from Hyper Binary, Nat Salih &amp;amp; Edward Richards b2b Frederick Sexton&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">Melbourne’s leading techno promoter, touring and events company Bunker returns to The SUBSTATION to celebrate its sixth birthday with a warehouse-style event featuring world-class techno acts from Europe alongside local talent. Experience a night of blistering and hypnotic music and accompanying visual installations in The SUBSTATION’S atmospheric, majestic industrial setting.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Bunker6.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Channels Festival</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/channels-festival/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Channels Festival" /><published>2019-02-07T13:30:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-02-07T13:30:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/channels-festival</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/whats-on/channels-festival/">&lt;p&gt;The 2019 Channels Festival, curated by Artistic Director Kelli Alred, will investigate how social, cultural and technological constructs impact individual and collective visibility and agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Australian and international artists have been invited to present works that expand our understanding of history, connectivity, power and place. Examining critical moments of transformation, concepts of community, cultural identity and gender, the festival will present artworks that blur fact with fiction to deconstruct notions of belonging, complicity and resistance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Channels Festival is pleased to be partnering with The SUBSTATION to present their 2019 festival keynote exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">The 2019 Channels Festival, curated by Artistic Director Kelli Alred, will investigate how social, cultural and technological constructs impact individual and collective visibility and agency.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/ChannelsFestival.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Discwoman feat. Umfang and Shyboi</title><link href="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/cool-room/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Discwoman feat. Umfang and Shyboi" /><published>2019-02-07T13:30:00+11:00</published><updated>2019-02-07T13:30:00+11:00</updated><id>https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/cool-room</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://thesubstation.org.au/archive/cool-room/">&lt;p&gt;DISCWOMAN has unquestionably changed the political landscape of dance music. Founded by Frankie Decaiza Hutchinson, Emma Burgess-Olson and Christine McCharen-Tran in September 2014, started as a two-day festival at Bossa Nova in New York, Discwoman has grown into a collective, artist agency, and event platform that unapologetically subverts expectations, breaks norms, and amplifies voices of the marginalised. In and outside of the club, they have fearlessly lead the global discourse around gender imbalance on club and festival lineups since their inception in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL ROOM is a collective and event series focused on changing conversations around representation and safety in electronic music, while creating a safer space for marginalised peoples to dance. Across varied sonic terrain, over four years and through parties, panels, and showcases, COOL ROOM has sought to highlight women, gender diverse folk, queers, and people of colour pushing boundaries in their work. Past Cool Room guests have included Steffi, Terre Thaemlitz (AKA DJ Sprinkles), Laurel Halo, and K-HAND.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL ROOM makes their debut at The SUBSTATION for a night of fierce, politically-charged techno, with dual international headliners to be announced.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Callum Flack Design</name></author><summary type="html">DISCWOMAN has unquestionably changed the political landscape of dance music. Founded by Frankie Decaiza Hutchinson, Emma Burgess-Olson and Christine McCharen-Tran in September 2014, started as a two-day festival at Bossa Nova in New York, Discwoman has grown into a collective, artist agency, and event platform that unapologetically subverts expectations, breaks norms, and amplifies voices of the marginalised. In and outside of the club, they have fearlessly lead the global discourse around gender imbalance on club and festival lineups since their inception in 2014.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://thesubstation.org.au/uploads/Cool.jpg" /></entry></feed>